what's up everybody it is the junkyard
love podcast episode 101 101 Dalmatians
and it's the man Keenan Harvey hurricane
Harvey himself on the podcast
Keenan is a very good friend of mine
we've been friends for many years
um we have our our distances we we've
been known to fight like brothers we uh
uh we disagree vastly and there are
certain times where I've actually like
taken a break on our friendship uh just
because I was going through things he
was going through things but it's so
cool how much you know we could realign
and Rehab a conversation and uh just
land right back right back in love with
a friend you know I I admire this person
dearly a lot of my life has been
um
my friends have been my family that's
really how how life is is has played out
for me I'm a lot closer to uh to my
friends than I have ever been to to a
lot of my family members um the Deep
like unconditional love I've felt from
from my friends I'm just very blessed to
have that and Keenan has been been a
huge part of that since I was a you know
in the younger years of my teenage years
me and him and a few other people we we
worked at the same Mall together so we
just kind of bonded we'd hang out after
work and it just stood into this
beautiful friendship so
um I'm coming from a place of you know
I'm talking to him as a city councilman
as a um someone who serves back in my
hometown
um under a role of a city councilman but
a lot of this is just I'm talking to
Keenan man this is just my friend he's
just a person he has this role um I
think he shows up very well in this
podcast as just you know not trying to
be anybody not trying to
um you know present himself as like I am
the city councilman or anything you know
we're just kind of bsing as friends and
and he happens to have these jobs and we
have a few conversations about them but
um
it weaves in and out I think it's a good
combo it's always really I'm blessed to
be able to just have conversations with
friends on here you know is is as crazy
as it is that I get to talk to these
like psychologists and scientists and
you know like a millionaires or like all
these like cool guests that I get to
have I also love the fact that I get to
have conversations with my buddies on
here you know I've always wanted to
leave room for that in my podcast in my
in my conversations and and just kind of
have it this open experience of of my
life you know these are different facets
of of of
um you know things that I'm interested
in
um but I'm also just just a dude who has
friends and I happen to have a podcast
and I could put a mic in front of them
and we can have cool conversations that
um you know hopefully in some ways
benefit or at least positively entertain
the listener so anyway without further
Ado it's episode one zero one thanks for
listening it's the junk I love podcast
with Keen on Harvey If you like the
episode please like subscribe comment
all that sort of stuff it helps the
algorithm I don't care about listeners
or view counter any of that sort of crap
I'm just doing what I'm doing but it
does help more people listen if you
think that it's beneficial share it
send a clip to your friend if you hit
follow if you could quickly on Spotify
or YouTube or Pandora or apple music or
wherever you listen to it if you do hit
like five stars it's just beneficial it
helps more people listen to it thank you
so much anyway let's get on with the
episode have better conversations with
ourselves
yeah
[Music]
knowledge is power
reality is
[Music]
interesting so it's not really even a
place for it's not really even the right
place for that then ice I suppose right
right and and that's why we use email or
uh
workshops or uh kind of town hall
type events or I've I've gone as far as
going door to door and asking people you
know their opinions on the topic so
you're a brave man
I would not want to do that especially
also yeah dude yeah um
yeah there's so many things to say about
that
um
excuse me
I think I had my vape pen too hard last
night or something I don't know
I was uh I was just in um I was just in
Michigan with my dad and uh I had taken
a few month break from smoking weed but
um I was just in Michigan with my dad
and like dude just smokes a lot and so
it was kind of a way to for us to to
bond I end up just being crazy stoned
the whole time so I feel like I'm I'm
still my lungs are still recovering from
that
um this is gonna turn into the Joe Rogan
uh Elon Musk interview where I'm gonna
get canceled for talking about weed yeah
yeah well let's let's do it over Zoom
let's uh like Keenan do you have that
blunt that I've sent you in the mail
like we both smoke
let me go get it uh that'd be too good
that'd be too good
um yeah well okay so
um my my podcast is actually like I mean
you say Rogan it's I like the
conversational aspect of Rogan's like
dude if we feel like talking about you
know your childhood trauma and then
aliens four minutes later and then like
city council stuff right after like Let
It Flow wherever it's gonna flow like
we'll just be us and whatever you know I
I have a few notes but I'm not overly
you know that's kind of what I expected
I'm chilling yeah that's what I like
that's what I like to do is just
conversations and then you know you
stumble upon cool stuff and you
elaborate and you know sometimes you end
up talking about like a you know the you
talk about the temperature of
refrigerators for 25 minutes somehow or
something and you know that's what it is
sometimes that's interesting I operate
better that way
with all these uh all these politicians
in my world they have What's called the
stump speech and they talk for like
three minutes about themselves and oh
I'm so and so and I my my grandma's
mother's cousin was on city council 32
years ago I just want to follow on their
footsteps and it's like that that's not
you just fire questions off I don't care
right right yeah so is that so like do
you think that all politicians are all
um you know council members have kind of
uh you know basically an elevator pitch
and they just kind of repeat it
throughout their lives like here's who I
am here's what's happened to me and
here's where why I'm here sort of thing
yep and they repeat it over and over and
over and they memorize it and I don't
operate that way so I not only am I on
Council but I've worked campaigns for
other people um to try to get good
people elected and so I've seen the same
elevator pitches from all different
candidates even their opponents uh over
and over it's it's
very very reductive yeah it's almost
like they you know you type how to make
a resume and then you follow a template
and they kind of like do that same thing
and then they eventually have their what
do you call the stump speech or stump
yeah it's called stunt speech yeah okay
well let me press you on yours what's
your stump speech what's your uh what's
your okay so like say somebody who
doesn't know you they've never heard of
you
um they're stumbling across like maybe
they they listen to my podcast maybe
it's the first time they listen to the
episode they don't have to know anything
about either of us uh let's let's put
the pressure on you what is your what's
your what's your intro here who are you
doing this is what I'm the worst at uh
because I naturally just don't like
talking about myself
um it's kind of kind of weird I do get
it because there is a certain level of
professionalism that people feel like
they're obligated to uphold but I'm
opposite I mean
I'm surprised you're not like giving a
disclaimer uh in the beginning of the
interview like viewer discretion is
advised because you know I'm gonna drop
some drop some curse words or whatever
um but no I'm I'm Keenan and Harvey uh
I'm a member of the Kelso City Council
full-time I'm a commercial insurance
agent for a large insurance broker where
I focus on Commercial
um uh risk mitigation and Commercial
liability for large business uh but I've
held jobs in the non-profit sector I was
the director of The Humane Society prior
to this position and then uh I was a
pseudo law enforcement officer for the
Washington State Department of
Corrections where I was in parole and
probation
sort of held jobs in public private and
non-profit sectors and then before I was
a parole and probation officer I worked
at a juvenile uh juvenile prison in an
integrated gang unit it was called the
Hawthorne unit at a maximum security
juvenile prison and then before that I
was I interned in college with a
juvenile Rehabilitation which was a
minimum security juvenile prison for
incarcerated youth but kind of to
reintegrate them back in the community
and so I have a bachelor's degree in
Criminal on Justice
um I'm graduating from Kelso High School
so naturally I don't know how to do math
very well but
um
no and that that's uh basically who I am
as a person
um since I was elected I've I've got my
uh a certificate of Municipal leadership
and then my Advanced certificate of
Municipal leadership which is
fairly unique there's not that many
elected uh people in the state of
Washington to to have their Advanced
certificate in Municipal leadership
um and then you know I'm active in the
custom Longview Chamber of Commerce on
their board I'm on the college Economic
Development Council board a member of
the vice president of Kelsey rotary now
um so I'm I'm not only am I active uh
and engaged but I kind of have my hat
many different rings to try to better
myself and kind of learn how to better
serve the city of Kelso
I love that well hey man just as your
friend like congrats like it's so
awesome you know I hope it doesn't this
doesn't sound condescending but you know
I'm proud of you I feel like you have
accomplished a lot I've known you for
many years so you know it's it's cool to
know you dude how did you um would you
say even from a young age that you had
like a leadership background like have
you always kind of been like this dude I
I mean looking at where you're at did
you plan on kind of ending up here or
no and it really happened uh
so I was elected four years ago but I
really kind of started to get
I I I think the wrong word's politically
active because people assume that like
attribute that to a negative now but um
I think it was about seven years ago
um six or seven years ago
I started following local politics and I
realized that at a local level
you can actually do more
um you can actually uh better your small
community
um because you have you're more Hands-On
with people your policy is more local
um and so I opted to start studying up
on local politics and then
I kind of had a prime opportunity to run
for custom city council and it was
partially because
the policies that my opponent at the
time was proposing
um were things that I thought were best
for the city and so I threw my ring and
I ended up winning
um nice yeah that's cool yeah it's it's
I think that's something that um you
know probably a lot of us sort of
learned I'm not super duped into the
world of politics but I think a lot of
us kind of saw you know the the lockdown
stuff and even before that you know I'll
just kind of like a little bit of the
madness that we've started having you
know what since 2015 or something in our
uh political realm I think a lot of us
kind of started as we got older
realizing oh this is all kind of nutty
this is all you know like this is almost
like a reality TV version of actual
politics that we're really following
intently
um and then you know you kind of look
around and realize there's a bit of
responsibility and there's there is a
bit more that you can do at a local
level
um than just following all of the the
national level stuff and and I think
it's it's actually pretty important and
I like that and I like that um
um
I don't know I mean I think we should
make it cool to to run for you know
local government I I I I think that that
really is probably where change
um that you actually see in your
everyday life versus what's shown to you
on your phone you know I think that's
really where it's where it can happen is
at a local level yeah and that's one of
my biggest compliances uh young people
tend to not get involved I mean they're
not even voting in elections they're not
uh they're not studying up on issues and
it's kind of been a
a retired person's game you know they
retire from the Mills and they're like
hey I need a new hobby but what I found
is that it kind of
leads to the same mentality over and
over and over
um and there's not there hasn't been a
whole lot of uh New Perspectives younger
and energetic uh excitement to be in the
political realm and
it's kind of led to I think some
stagnation especially in Kelso in
Longview as you know
um we haven't seen a ton of growth
um
comparative to other other
municipalities around us we haven't seen
a ton of growth in development and I
think a fresh perspective is
kind of necessary at this point what's
your way what's your way of going about
that I mean I know that I saw like like
you're active on social media I think
it's already a good thing um it seems
like you're like unafraid to get your
voice out there and talk about things
which is also another good thing I saw
that you had made a kind of a video like
you're running for a re-election you
made a video and when I saw that I was
like oh cool you know more of this let's
do more of this you know a few minute
video of kind of who you are what's your
background what are your kind of talking
points you know that goes a long way
that really you know it could catch the
attention of people who are scrolling
through social media not really paying
attention to any of that sort of stuff
it might draw them into it a little bit
more
yeah and in the public realm there's
kind of this ideology that when you post
on social media or when you're active on
social media that it's they call it an
echo chamber
and I would make the argument that yeah
that's that's probably partially true
because you're speaking to mostly people
that agree with you or uh news sites the
the news sites on Facebook that are you
know
localized uh we have one called Cowlitz
County News there's Cowlitz County News
uncensored
um things like in those pages but my
argument would be that my reach of
people
um to try to gauge public interest is
significantly larger than just going and
talking to your five neighbors
um so
I would much prefer my echo chamber over
somebody that isn't active on social
media or isn't
um talking to a broader range of people
you know if if I'm wrong and I post
something on Facebook they'll tell me
right away
um and
you know you'll hear about it from
people on in the social media realm so
it's kind of what we need and it's kind
of in my opinion what I was elected to
do is be transparent be open be honest
speak to as many people as possible and
engage my policy based off of that
well I think also awareness is such a
superpower you know being aware that hey
this is an echo chamber there's a lot of
potentiality for me to not get all the
different sides of the story or
different opinions that that may
actually matter and um I don't think
that means that you know we we put the
name Echo chamber on all of social media
and so we ignore it you know that's a
bit foolish but I think that uh yeah
having that awareness of uh of of of
understanding like cool we could really
get a consensus for maybe what my echo
chamber what my side sort of thinks and
then um you know elaborate on that um in
other areas so dude I think um
it really is a pretty important thing
you know we have
I think about like what social media and
what the internet is for I guess
Humanity as a whole you know it's
actually pretty crazy you know it's the
way that we've done things for so long
and just over the last however many
years we have this this thing we call
social media and it has this unserious
Arc to it but it actually is
um you know uh Twitter now called x uh
you know they say it's the the Public
Town Square or whatever and there's a
lot of
there's a lot of people who make fun of
that and there's a lot of ways that
that's not true but there is a lot of
ways that it is in some ways and I think
that um there's valuable
there's valuable con conversations and
valuable contributions that could happen
on social media that we shouldn't
Overlook it's a bit foolish for us to
ignore it
right well and uh kind of keeping up
with Trends is important so I I joke
around about uh Tick Tock and uh and
kind of how the younger generation
chooses to use
uh Tick Tock so I'm I'm in my early 30s
and you know I made it through the
Myspace days where uh you had a top
eight and you you put a song on your
profile and uh you feel like we were
probably on each other's top eight to be
honest oh yeah I I'm pretty sure we were
um but that was also how kind of how we
how we flirted with girls hey will you
be on the number one by top eight yeah
and then there was this brand new social
media called Facebook that popped up
well
so when I was younger it was actually uh
the aim uh
aim what was he some of the other MSN
message MSN Messenger I was on that yeah
that was big in college County but most
of the uh other uh
parts of the United States use
um different chat options but now
they're kind of the running joke with
the younger generation is hey Facebook
is for your mom and dad and aunts and
uncles and connecting with them but
Snapchat uh Tick Tock I mean whatever
the next platform is for actually
communicating so how do we
recognize that technology is drastically
changing how do we reach more people and
younger people to get a different
perspective and I have in a sense failed
because I don't use tick tock I I am on
Snapchat but you know I'm still talking
to Mike the only snapshots I send to
people are like my top 20 friends so
yeah you keep sending me shirtless pics
man I don't know why uh no I mean a year
last year so
hey I voted a lot you can vote once a
day and I voted every day you know that
so
um man I well I think it's um I will say
though you know as younger people so say
you guys had someone come into your
vicinity into your world of councilman
and stuff that was younger and they were
using Tick Tock I'm sure you'd probably
be the first one to go cool excellent it
seems like you know a lot about Tick
Tock that is important like run with it
how can I help you know I think that you
would be um you know not not against
that sort of thing I think do you think
that there's a
what are if any the innate differences
between our social medias I mean because
I I think that
you know as much as different age groups
spend different things different times
on on various things um I I do think
that you're right about Facebook being
there's something about it being kind of
an older man's game but I don't think
that that's just an age thing or a
generation thing I think it's how it
happened in our society like Facebook
kind of was the first online
community that was an actual reflection
of our community so you know I I live in
Austin now but you know I completely
understand and I completely see and I
still have Facebook of it really is like
a local community there's there's a
difference between what you say and what
you post and what kind of interactions
happen on Facebook versus on Tick Tock
or SnapChat or Instagram or any of these
sorts of things
um and and there is still
um
well I I I don't know you know it's it
maybe at the time when it first came out
like think about how different Facebook
was when it first started like I always
make the joke you know and this is like
cringy to repeat back but like we didn't
think about it when we were young but I
would quote word for word Kid Cudi
lyrics on my Facebook post and like I
used the n-word on my Facebook post and
now it's like whoa like I would never do
that because I understand that that's
just like an insane thing to do but back
then you don't you don't think that way
and it's not that like like I would say
that I was an idiot or that I was just a
young fool like no that's really just
kind of the nature of how things were we
didn't think about those things deeply
when Facebook first came about it was
just kind of a different beast but it
did really grab the local community
thing and I don't know I doubt that it's
just our small town that has that I bet
you there's small towns all across the
U.S that kind of like their local
Facebook Community is still sort of
going strong as an actual reflection of
what's happening in their Community what
do you think about that yeah how do you
think that Karen was born I mean that's
that's really it's them from uh
complaining about local
issues on their Facebooks in you know
maybe I'm wrong on that but uh we have
it was Facebook really created certain
subgroups in the community that are that
are localized and I think the intent was
initially good but now it's a little bit
um
it it's it's it's kind of morphed into
kind of a complaining Fest you know I'm
I'm a part of many different like local
localized Facebook groups to to try to
gauge public interest again but you know
every every so often or not every so
often pretty frequently you hear oh so
many so-and-so speeding down the
neighborhood tell them to slow down oh
that's wrong or did you hear that boom
uh
the the random booms I don't get that
not anymore but that's kind of what
Facebook just has morphed into but I
think the original intent was yeah
localized communication a broader reach
of people
um this is a a way to connect and then
reconnect with uh past friends I'm
friends on Facebook with people I went
to high school with and I haven't seen
since so you know I think it's kind of a
double-edged sword where it has a lot of
good qualities but
um I
to you that
when we first started using the platform
Facebook I mean it was kind of no hold
bar we posted whatever we wanted
um and and got away with it how on Earth
we haven't been canceled from our past
uh post and I feel like people are going
to start taking up my my past Facebook
yeah please everyone listening dig deep
into Keenan's trust me there's some good
stuff on it it was it was good back then
well dude it's it's we you know it's
it's a maturity thing as as people in
general you know we all kind of like
dude who gave us this power to post
whatever the heck we want and we're 14
anyway but I think that even a 14 year
old back then is a different 14 year old
than today you know they know uh their
their awareness of the general public
outside of just their community in their
in their town is very different than how
how we saw things you know I think about
it with the podcast a lot of like
you know
am I talking to the people that I know
are listening or am I talking to new
listeners am I talking to people in my
hometown or like my core listeners that
like continuously show up or am I trying
to talk to like the broad everyone as a
whole you know and I think that kind of
changes the way that we that we interact
with things you know
and I yes and I think to an extent back
to the back to the point about kind of
posting what we wanted at 14. I think
you do still see
um every time a new platform comes up
you do still see a continuation of that
so on Tick Tock there are
14 13 12 year olds that are posting uh
inappropriate things that I know 10
years from now they're going to look
back and say yeah I probably shouldn't
have posted that right but the benefit
to the new platforms I think is really
the learning aspect so I don't have a
tick tock but I do watch
um the reels on Instagram and
uh and on Facebook uh that are you know
almost directly posted from Tick Tock
onto those other platforms and I think
the benefit of those
um
of of that specifically The Tick Tock
platform is that uh
ability to learn in such a short amount
of time I think it's what a 14 second
video of Max or something like that on
Tick Tock I don't really remember but
you can post a really long video but
there's there's a ton of short ones yeah
right but the ability to learn
um on a different platform than YouTube
That's not several hours long you know
cooking videos hey but uh uh you saute
your veggies you boil the noodles you do
all this and I think you can you can
kind of
make that into a public into my into my
public space
um you really educate people on
uh the municipal aspects
um like here's what uh if you if you do
this this will happen you know in in a
short amount of time so you keep their
attention span you can really make it a
positive I'm not so sure that we're
there yet since I still see people doing
two-step dances
um which uh random lyrics but you know I
well we'll do this this thing where
there's uh there's both the very
unserious and the serious mixed in on
the same you know platforms you know
I've had this guy uh uh Eric Weinstein
is his name he's like a physicist a
mathematician I really like this the way
that he thinks um and he he's pointed
out I mean a couple years ago he is
basically saying you know we have these
uncir we have this cute little blue bird
you know it's it's this little app and
we post our thoughts on there but it's
actually at the same time there's
various serious conversations that are
happening there and I think Tick Tock
and all social media is kind of a
reflection of that you know it's there
is way so I guess
um and uh I mean somebody else can look
up the statistics for this or um you
know Jamie pulled up uh but there is
apparently the younger generation gen Z
and stuff
um Tick Tock is the where they go for
their information so whereas we might
you know you and I wanna you know hey
how do I change you know a drum break on
my on my you know Ford Tempo we would
look it up on YouTube they look it up on
Tick Tock so the search function on Tick
Tock is how they're learning to do a lot
of things and I guess there's some sort
of stats I've heard other people discuss
on podcasts that that is the most
commonly used Search tool nowadays is
Tick Tock and so it's basically short
videos of you know and I even use it so
um I've been dude I've been working out
for a long time I've always liked
working out going to the gym muscle
building that sorts of things but over
the last probably like four or five
months I've found myself using Tick Tock
and just kind of like relearning
watching these videos of people who
break down oh you want uh you want to do
a shoulder workout well here's what
you're going to do and they condense in
35 seconds with these visuals and it's
perfectly sounding and it's this nice
cool video but it's 35 seconds and I
learn all this information that you know
might have taken me over a 10 minute
video of watching someone Ramble On so
there is it's powerful man you know I
think we're we're getting rid of like
the we're cutting around a lot of the
fat here with with some of the social
media and getting right to the point
which our Young Generation really likes
yeah and that's that's going to be
important for information
um
you know in the future and and kind of
learning as a society so that's it's
it's it's exciting um it's a little bit
scary uh but because I I feel like
people kind of Chase that uh
chase that high instead of slowing down
they're like I need that information I
need to need it now
um instead of
taking a breath and actually learning a
trade and I think they're again
more or less a double-edged sword
because
um sometimes
things that you can learn on Tick Tock
are a specific trade and if you cut
corners and you you reference a 35
second video you can run into some
situations where it to be frank like
working on car videos it can be
dangerous if you don't do things the
right way so kind of condensing it well
the information is great
um sometimes I think you need to slow
down and learn the right way yeah no 100
and I also think that you know we look
at where we're at as a society these 35
second videos are no replacement for a
mechanic who's been doing it for 35
years right you know like there really
is a lot you know don't don't go you
know just because your your grandpa kind
of talks slow and it seems like he's
telling you things that don't seem to be
important don't underestimate that the
man has something to teach you you know
it's great to get the 35 second video
it's great to kind of get a condensed
version so you can be empowered to do it
on your own whatever but uh there's a
lot of the more long-form ways of
learning that are equally as valuable
you know yeah and I think I think it
kind of has on a broader scope it's kind
of attributed to so because I'm on the
Chamber of Commerce board
um which is small business focus
um most of the small businesses in town
are having trouble hiring employees and
it's not necessarily the initial hiring
of employees but it's keeping the
employees there and I think the short
attention span that that chasing the
quick information has kind of led to
um
I don't want to use the word uh ADHD but
you know it's kind of kind of that
mentality that uh they're so rapid with
their uh with their judgments are almost
impulsive that it's kind of created a
different societal problem
um or they don't want to hold on to jobs
for very long because they're not
getting that satisfaction if that makes
sense
um yeah no I think that is important
thing I think that we're kind of uh you
know this I don't even know if it's the
correct terminology at this point but
kind of just like drained of our
dopamine we're getting these dopamine
hits and it's like when we stop getting
them so consistently it starts to kind
of feel bad and then we um yeah I mean
there's there's something again it's
good but there's also a lot of value in
slowing down in in kind of um you know I
I guess being present with with what's
going on
um instead of because because you can
have a lot of momentum of just all right
what's next what's better what's better
than this what's better than this and
then you're really like almost uh trying
to like run away from your feelings of
like it's okay to have a shitty day at
work dude like it's okay like some days
at work the whole day is just crazy you
know and that's okay that doesn't mean
that you need to completely switch
career Fields you know maybe you know if
that's happening all the time you know
live your life and and you know I don't
think any of this stuff is really worth
us being miserable
um you know there's there's no you know
any sort of job is chasing the carrot on
the stick of sorts right but uh there
there is
not every day can be amazing and so fun
at work you know that's really not not
the truth you know maybe eventually for
some people that is somewhere where we
can land but it really is the truth of
uh being able to handle the days that
aren't nearly as fun as the day before
at work
absolutely and I've kind of learned that
I learned that in my whole day
uh
uh you know so I I so I jumped into the
political sphere when I was in my late
20s
um and
I uh I just got a pretty cool nickname a
few weeks ago they called me hurricane
Harvey yeah
supposed to be a disc but um and I think
it's because
being young and energetic uh young young
in the political world uh
I tend to legislate and I tend to lead
vocally but also
um
efficient or I try to try to push for
the most efficiency as possible and in
the public lifestyle in that especially
in municipalities
the the they move at like half the speed
of smell man you can't get anything done
quickly
um and so I don't operate that way so if
I want
a policy to be passed I'll put it on the
agenda and I'll pass it
and and so I think that's kind of led to
a perception of me that uh I'm a loose
cannon or uh hurricane Harvey but it's
uh it's kind of by Nature uh me trying
to push
the the city of Kelso to be more
efficient
um and I happen to like the nickname so
I'm going to run with it I'm gonna put
it on all my campaign signs and
everything
um
no Rugrats but hurricane Harvey yeah
spell it wrong keen on
those 18 year olds that forgot their
so they had to get it tattooed on them
uh right when they turned 18. was it was
that UJ
I mean in my defense in my defense I was
17.
my first tattoo I literally got the
entire right side of my body um tattooed
uh yeah anyway
we've all been there you know represent
with your last name what do you think
about so I mean I like how you said that
you kind of embraced this nickname
though you know what what are the what
are the downsides of this of this way of
thinking what are the downsides of being
hurricane Harvey
the downsides of hurricane Harvey no and
I think it comes back to a perception
um I think that's kind of the the inner
the inner struggle between uh some of
the
we'll call them more experience I don't
want to I don't want to disparage
anybody for being older and being in
public life for a long time but they've
been set in their ways and I think
they're when they when they're
challenged by a new
way of thinking or a new ideology or a
new way of governing
um that's when uh they get defensive
so uh
I you know I think it's a delicate
balance between kind of how I operate
and and recognizing that from a city
we're Bound by
um many rules regulations case law state
law and so that's partial partially the
reason why we
have to take things in a slow approach
but finding that delicate balance
between hey how are we as efficient as
possible but also uh with respect to
laws and how we have to upgrade yeah
yeah no it's definitely it's definitely
um you know both and you know it's not
that I do see ways in which you know the
the swiftness of hey this thing needs to
be passed let's just get it done that is
great you know but there's also uh you
know
um it's it's all of us that are that are
living here you know it's not just
because the young way sounds exciting
and and right now and it gets more stuff
done doesn't mean that there's not
valuable stuff in in the old way you
know it's really both I I like this um
um uh I have a one of the spiritual
teachers I listen to his name is ramdas
he was a he real name was Richard Albert
he used to be a Harvard professor and
then he did psychedelics with Timothy
Leary and went over and got a guru over
um you know in the Eastern world but uh
uh he would talk about how he would have
um you know spiritual people would sit
down and they have you know some sort of
um uh what is it it's not ashram what's
the uh um a mantle basically of you know
it has you know pictures of Jesus and
their their Guru and whatever and then
he would always put somebody that's like
really hard for him to love he would
always put this uh you know like a
picture of like Ronald Reagan or
somebody who's like in in the political
spear who's not as easy to love is you
know looking looking at a picture of
Jesus and uh his way of doing it is kind
of like hey they have to come too
they're here too you know it's easy to
love these other beings but there's also
these other people who are part of our
community and I think that's where a lot
of us get a little caught up as we're
like well we all need to be more like
this I wish everybody else was more like
this and you end up pushing people away
who do have valuable opinions and the
truth about the Melting Pot in the U.S
is is that it is all of us it's not we
need to be more conservative we need to
be more liberal it's like hey the truth
of it is is we have some people who are
liberal and we have some people who are
conservative
um in in we're all here so how do we
make that work with all of us because
there's value to both opinions it's not
just we all need to be one exact way
it's it's really like bringing everyone
along
and I've definitely noticed that
[Music]
um
in in not only city life but my personal
life but in the city lifestyle in the
municipal life
um finding a common ground has been kind
of increasingly difficult but what we
forget is that
regardless of where you stand on a
position our whole goal is to better the
community
um just because we disagree on how to
get there doesn't mean one's more wrong
than the other
um and and I challenge that mentality
every once in a while by just simply
saying well we've tried it your way why
can't we try it mine
um and it does I do receive quite a bit
of pushback pretty frequently but
um
at some point you know doing the same
thing over and over what was the old
adage the old saying uh it's uh
stupidity is trying the same thing over
and over and expecting different results
I think that's kind of where why we are
where we are so let's try something new
I'm sure Austin is having a similar
conversation on uh homelessness and the
uh
the the homeless homeless issues in
their in the city Austin uh we have a
neighboring city the city of Longview
um
that they're having a serious homeless
issue um Kelso is a little bit better
obviously I'm not
that we have homeless people but
um we operate on our side of the river
so for your listeners listeners that
don't know the Cowlitz County area
there's two cities basically connected
um there's no distance in between the
two cities
um for sake of the conversation uh the
only thing separating us is a very short
River
um obviously there's different boundary
lines but uh for the sake of the
conversation the river is what separates
us
um and we operate completely differently
so where where they're having serious
conversations on homelessness and how to
solve homelessness which it's never
going to be solved but at least uh make
an impactful difference on the
conversation in the city of Kelso
operates a little bit differently
um and so finding that middle ground and
saying hey
your way is more right than our way or
our way is more right than your way
isn't benefiting anybody let's find a a
pathway forward since we're all trying
to achieve the same goal which is
to better um the whole Community
yeah I mean that's like one of the most
important things is really you know it's
so easy to get into the weeds of all
this stuff and then at all times it's
it's probably like you know probably
something you find yourself doing is
trying to bring everyone in the room
okay cool we made some some cool
distance on that we made some uh you
know we got into the Weeds on that and
that's great but we got to rewind and we
gotta back up and go what are we all
doing this for our our answer is
actually trying to better our community
are our answers and our our um you know
even you know arguments are going to
happen in these things but are the
arguments getting so far into the weeds
that they're just silly or are they
really getting to where we're solving
the problem and making our community
Better Stronger
yep and so uh I'm up for re-election
right now
um and one of my focuses is going to be
um kind of taking a step back as an
elected and uh you know it fell on deaf
ears or it didn't resonate with uh so I
was talking to a a room full of
um
full of uh the older population and I
used the term they doing too much uh I
think that kind of uh
that kind of is true for electives too
they're trying to get fancy they're
trying to do uh do too much
um where they're passing policies that
aren't going to make an impactful
difference and so one of my current
campaign topics is hey let's take a step
back let's focus on
um
the bare minimum let's fix our street
lights let's
potholes
um and that once we make an impactful
difference with the basics that's when
we can kind of graduate to
you know a broader scope of uh or I
guess a more narrow scope of of
different ideas but until we fix our
basic issues we can't
afford or we can't push to change uh we
can't we can't do too much because we're
kind of bound by uh our failing current
infrastructure if that makes sense why
do you think they're doing too much like
like what what is that why would they
think that that's the best way to go
about solving the problem
so
the what comes first the chicken or the
egg um so when you're talking about
business growth and development in this
in a community uh
you entice businesses to move into an
area or into a into a community by uh
by fixing your amenities right so
about six uh six months ago uh we had a
topic come across our agenda which is uh
pushing for a kayak a kayak boat launch
in the city of Kelso which is pretty
unique we have a small uh small river
that runs right through the center of
town and it's pretty underutilized
um and so one of the council members
proposed uh putting a kayak boat launch
in uh on the cow human River well
the idea is fantastic uh I agree
um the idea is fantastic but we can't at
this point put in a new park
when we have other parks that are
dilapidated falling apart
so they're trying to entice new
businesses or new growth and development
with new parks but we still have failing
current infrastructure so that uh
Chicken and the Egg scenario you know
how do we entice businesses to come to
our community yes I agree we kind of
have to do both we have to push for new
and exciting ideas but we also need to
fix our current
uh issues that we're facing now yeah you
can't just slap some new paint over the
rust and pretend the rust isn't there
you know I do see how that's very
important man that must be a huge
balance of just you know just the work
that all of you guys do is
of course the shiny new thing is fun of
course it's gonna sell of course that's
like a I mean that's a good election
point of like hey look at this whole
elaborate thing and we can have kayaks
and you could do like a a 3D render of
it and you know you can even make some
sort of AI video nowadays people playing
in the caluman river on kayaks and just
seeing that would be like whoa cool I
want to do that yes let's vote for that
but you're totally right yeah if other
things are falling by the wayside how do
you how do you I mean even just outside
of the specific situation how do we
balance that like in in communities and
and how to how to counsel people
um you know keep that in mind how do we
not get rid of or or neglect the things
that are kind of rusting out while we're
also contributing to the new exciting
fun stuff
you know again I think it is a delicate
balance as you stated
um but you know we can't entice new
businesses I mean something something as
simple as painting crosswalks and curves
or pressure washing our our buildings
um or pressure washing uh to the biggest
one of the bigger eyesores right
the bridge that separates
um the two Longview from Kelso and it's
it's got mold and uh I mean we live in
the Pacific Northwest so it's
um
exposed to inclement weather every
single day and so you know cleaning our
critical infrastructure beautifying our
our infrastructure and then doing the uh
doing the shiny new new things when we
have the resources and this the staff to
to complete those tasks right so it's
the same Department that is uh
maintaining our Parks uh and our roads
and our water so focusing on cleaning up
our current infrastructure and then we
can move on and graduate to uh putting
the new shiny thing and then that's
that's my opinion that's how I prefer to
operate
hmm yeah yeah I see yeah I I guess I was
just kind of visualizing like you know
you go into this new cool kayak launch
but your car gets a flat tire because
the road on the way there is just giant
potholes and stuff so yeah that that is
probably like a you know uh a balance
that's difficult to strike in trying to
draw you know try you guys are probably
all like look no this is important look
no this is important and um into a
little bit of all of it is important but
I think that yeah the community members
have to understand you know
um it's cool to get the new exciting
thing but we also got to take care of
what we have you know that's that's
always been a rule of I mean you've
always kind of been a car guy that's
probably something you'll hear often is
like that's that's how you have nice
things is you take care of nice things
you know like it's I don't know I always
kind of just buy the [__] box and fix
them up and that's why I have six
projects sitting in the driveway and
yeah that's actually very true yeah okay
well I'll say the people that you're
around you know yes
Mark and Bobby and Dave
yeah
cool um well uh yeah dude Okay cool so
so what else um what what are your other
running points on on this re-election
and um uh why are they important to you
uh so this election again I'm I'm
running on
uh fixing our critical infrastructure
it's gonna be a huge Focus so our Police
Department
um
our Police Department is I would argue
probably
top five
police departments in the state of
Washington
um they're super polished they have in
fantastic leadership they uh
they've achieved a lot they're properly
trained
um and I think that by nature is because
prior councils have focused uh almost
hyper focused on
one of the Departments and that's our
Police Department
um and there I I have so much respect
and so much high regard for them but in
the focusing on one Department they've
kind of
not neglected it's a poor word a poor
word choice but they they haven't
focused on other departments so right
now uh the cityic also has 14 million
dollars in backlog Road repair
and we still only have one full-time or
it's one and a half full-time
equivalents in our street road
department
so we have one person to maintain
everything or one and a half people to
maintain every single Road
um and so Staffing up our street and
road department uh getting some of that
infrastructure taken care of
um and that street road department also
is in charge of our facilities
maintenance our building maintenance our
signage our uh our Parks
um our water and water and sewer and so
really getting back to basics with that
department and let's step up let's
promote growth in that department
um yes it's going to cost us some money
up front but I believe the reward will
uh will increase kind of tenfold in the
future
um so you know making those Investments
now so other councils don't have to
carry the burden for our understaffed
our understaffed
um
area of our city is that is that a
matter of allocation of current
resources or is that a matter of drawing
importance to get more resources towards
that problem
so it's it's it I don't know so we we
run a pretty lean budget right now
um I I am proposing uh increasing our
budget knowing that for a few years
we're probably going to go in red but we
need to take care of our current
infrastructure and we're not we're not
maintaining our current infrastructure
at the at the level that we should right
now and I think we're really feeling the
effects of Prior councils you know 10 20
30 years ago
yeah I know that that's a very important
thing is that that what you do isn't
just for right now it has Downstream
it's going to have Downstream effects
and it has to it's kind of a long game
of of you know building a structure
that's continuously fixing and improving
itself while it's fixing improving the
city
yeah future future Council it might be
this Council we're going to be faced
with a really tough decision so we have
a beautiful old building on our West uh
our west side of the city it's called
Catlin Hall
um and we allocated a couple hundred
thousand dollars for a root repair uh
obviously the roof needs replaced um
it's a 100 year old building it's a it's
a staple of of of the neighborhood that
it's in
um and we found out
just yesterday that the bid
um to renovate Catlin Hall is actually
1.6 million dollars
so we're going to be faced with hey
if we can if it's feasible at all how do
we
you know swallow the pill to
fix the building or is it a lost cause
at this point and
it's gonna be a really tough decision in
the future um kind of finding that happy
medium is going to be really important
because it's a it is a gem of the
building I'm not sure if you remember it
it's the one that's uh in the spray park
uh the splash pad spray park uh the big
building cabinet Hall
um in the west side of kelsa wait is it
is that the one that's uh so it's next
to like Big Lots and Joanne's Fabrics
there the old Catlin pool
oh yeah yeah man one time um one time I
was swimming there when it was a pool
and someone pulled a knife on me and I
told on them
I just remember I was getting in trouble
for running on the uh running on the
pool deck
oh well that's what you get you could
have broken your arm I know you see here
you are like here you are saying oh I
almost got shanked and here I am saying
oh I I got in trouble for running
hahaha
I know I wasn't trying to represent as a
whole it's not like a place where people
get knives pulled on them all the time
but I just remember like I think that
I'm self-reflective because I was like I
don't know why I had to tell on the guy
probably could have just handled that on
my own but uh yeah just get stitches
Jake I know dude that is still haunting
me around that's why I left the town
actually because I was you know he just
got out of prison and I was afraid he'd
come for me so
um no no that's funny okay cool yeah
that's uh yeah I could see how that's
like that's it's hard to navigate I mean
what what a you know nearly impossible
task but you know hats off to you guys
for trying to solve these things and you
know putting your
putting your your passion for the
community you know trying to angle it
into things that are better for the for
the future of the community and and
right now you know I always love the
anybody I think what it takes to be a
leader is constantly thinking of that
adage of um you know you're you're
planting the seeds in the ground
so your grandchildren could sit in the
shade of the tree you know in in that
that sort of mindset of um you know we
got to do some hard work but but it'll
pay off and and we'll establish these
structures that will you know run
themselves in in some sort of ways and
the payoff will be uh you know plentiful
for the future generation so I think
that's cool
well in the renovation at Catlin Hall is
really a reflection of how prior
councils have led they've deferred the
maintenance until now and now we're
stuck with responsibility so changing
the the total ideology in the city where
hey we need to take care of our current
infrastructure so future councils don't
have to have the same issue uh have we
you know replaced the siding
um added those Ada ramps that are
required now to replace the Windows
replace the doors you know one thing a
year we wouldn't have we wouldn't be
stuck with a 1.6 million dollar bill in
one year but they they've deferred the
maintenance on that building so they're
prior governance is really affecting our
current records
okay um the this is just uh it's it's
been on my mind since you mentioned it
is the homelessness things I kind of
want to I kind of want to go back to
that I think that's always kind of an
interesting conversation
um it's it's this uh it's this
conversation that sometimes feels a
little bit weird to have because you
almost feel like you're being
insensitive to those people because
obviously they're people but it needs to
be discussed
um you know we have kind of these on the
internet and in certain places in the
U.S
um you know they where they they we want
to call them the d-homed or dehoused or
something and um I don't know I feel
like our conversation around it gets a
little strange and it's a very should be
a very serious conversation I mean
there's uh San Francisco for example I
mean the amount of homeless people is
just it's just an unimaginable number
and it's it's really like like for the
future of civilizations that you can't I
mean that's
it's bad news you know there's a lot of
bad stuff that can come out of that but
obviously it's not just you know oh just
all right we'll delete it and tell them
they can't be homeless you know like
tell them no you know so there's clearly
something happening there so what what
do you think that um I mean you
mentioned that Kelso seems to be doing a
pretty decent job with the homeless what
do you think that they do good that
bigger cities might be able to learn
from so like how does a small community
handle
um you know something like the Homeless
Problem
um in a way that other big cities can
reflect on um and then and then after
that I would love to open up the
conversation just about mental health
because obviously the core of
homelessness is mental health like these
are our brothers and sisters who are
sick as [__] they're so sick and you
know there's a conversation that could
happen there so but first like I guess
what uh what do you guys do what do we
do well in Kelso and what could like
bigger cities maybe look at and reflect
at
so the the problem is actually really
historical from about
2012 2013. this so this uh back in uh
back in 2012 2013
um just right right about when I was
graduating college back to Kelso
Longview
um the there was a non-profit that
opened up and they put a homeless uh a
low or a no barrier homeless
uh not a shelter that's that's not the
terminology they use anymore but
um homeless facility smack dab in the
middle of Kelso uh the low barrier model
uh basically says there's no
um no constraints for you to live
in our homeless facility uh and so by
Nature it created a huge uh hot spot for
crime
or calls for service for our Police
Department or uh massive
um and they were staying in a building
that was rented or leased by the County
Commissioners
um so the county the county governing
board at least that facility to the
nonprofit and so the city of Kelso
really didn't have a stay in our zoning
or code
um whether that could be there
so that sparked code changes and so the
homeless camps or low barrier facilities
are
there the
requirements to put them in the city of
Kelso now are much more strict finally
that facility was
shut down
um and it kind of pushed
uh the homeless issue into a neighboring
City at the same time the city of Kelso
passed a no camping ordinance
uh are no camping ordinance so there was
some case law that was passed uh you
know in the same era uh that basically
said it's not illegal to be homeless
if there's no public forum for places to
stay uh for for homeless people to stay
the city has to allow them to sleep in
public locations so uh
effectively the city of Kelso passed an
anti-camping ordinance but our
anti-camping ordinance complies 100 with
the case law because we allow uh
somebody that's homeless to sleep in the
public domain from 9 00 P.M to 6 in the
morning
so we're giving them a place to sleep
um
so
just about every morning at six at six
o'clock when there's a homeless person
sleeping or Police Department well and
it's I've seen these interactions
um
they'll go to the a homeless person
sleeping in a public location and say
hey guys time to wake up for the day
let's uh get get moving oftentimes the
homeless people will think our Police
Department our police department will
thank them and they'll move on for the
day and so we allow them to uh
the uh a place to sleep publicly
um and it's that enforcement in that
mutual respect between our police
department and the homeless population
that is kind of kept our numbers or our
our community blacked out
um
so our just the enforcement of the
ordinances uh has has really helped
passing good governance prior has really
helped not only the public perception
but also the mutual respect between the
homeless people and our police
department and that the that mentality
is not being shared with neighboring
cities and so that's why they're having
the issues that they are
um do you do you think I mean obviously
that's not a forever solution but that
does seem to be
um uh you know useful for what we're
handed so so so the neighboring cities
are not allowing camping in public
places overnight is that is that what
you're saying 24 7 365. so right now
there's a beautiful smack dab in the
center of the city of uh City of
Longview
um and they they
allow them to sleep there until more
recently they allow them to sleep there
and the public perception is that the
City of Longview is not doing anything
there's tents there's people defecating
and urinating in the middle of a
beautiful park there were some uh high
school students that were trying to take
their senior their prom photos in the
park and they couldn't because uh of the
aggressiveness of the homeless people
that were staying there yeah yeah and
from from the city perspective
um
and I guess for my personal opinion
we we can't
I I don't think we should be lumping
every homeless person into the same
category of course you know there's a
broader uh it's a much broader
discussion because there are so locally
in the city of Kelso they just uh
produce new statistics they're not City
because the Cowlitz County in general
um there's over 2 200 homeless people
uh and you know the uh first for a
community of 100 and 111 000 people I
believe is what our county is at right
now
um that's kind of a that's kind of high
number and kind of densely packed in the
in the middle of the two cities the city
of Houston city they don't Branch out to
clam or Castle Rock
um
but
there's multiple different types of
homeless people right there's a people
that
they're not lost causes they just don't
want the help they want to be left alone
they don't want government they don't
want the authority they don't want the
structure
um but there are the homeless people
that are down on their luck they're
sleeping in a car with their kids
they're
sleeping on the streets and they
you know for you know sometimes at no
fault of their own have fallen on Hard
Times you know we're all kind of a
paycheck or two away from having to be
classified as homeless uh you know that
the the
statistics do include people sleeping
from couch to couch it's not just the
people that are in your face
um and so
What in in my opinion focusing on the
people that want the help
um and we're talking about
a couple hundred people out of the two
out of the 2200 that are sleeping in the
streets the ones that are in your face
uh those are the ones that we should be
enforcing our ordinance on but we should
you know kind of take a step back and
look at the people that want the help
you know increase our housing Supply
um figure out ways through public policy
that we can uh build more doors with uh
Adu ordinances with tiny home villages
with low-income housing even some
subsidized housing uh figure out how to
focus Less on the ones that are in our
face and more on the ones that are
actually wanting to help and so that's
kind of the Crux of the issue it seems
like cities are focusing on the ones
that are
they're focusing on getting the people
off the streets that don't want the help
uh the city along you just put in a uh a
homeless Camp they called Hope Village
they spent 3.4 million dollars there's
only 40 doors and it is a low to no
barrier housing housing first
uh facility so spending 3.6 or yeah 3.6
million dollars is the total bill
spending that on the 200 people so less
than one percent of the population
um was probably not the best use of
their resources had they just enforced
their ordinance and then allocated that
3.6 million dollars to a housing project
or
in conjunction with changing their
zoning codes to allow for tiny home
Villages or uh kind of zero lot line
developments
um and and increase the doors in the
city they probably would have taken a
more significant dent out of
the actual problem
yeah no I think that's important I think
that's actually like something that's
that's I mean what what you're pointing
at is something that we need to as
societies and communities all over
really remember is not be focusing on
the loud Fringe you know like like as
easy as as it is for you know the the
homeless person who's like really loud
and there's kind of seem dangerous so
you want to walk on the other side of
the street and that sort of thing as
easy as it is to like think they
represent all of all of people who are
um just not at the best moment in their
life you know that doesn't mean that
like they're representative of all of
homeless so I think it's almost more
difficult shooting in our shooting
ourselves in the foot by trying to
overly focus and spending so many
resources on trying to help that version
of of people who are down on their Luck
versus
um you know the things that you said
like people who are surfing couches
people are just just having a tough time
you know people you know think about
like dude I I've been through I I didn't
thinking about like my instability as a
person if I didn't have close
friendships to help me out through my
hard points you know like a bad breakup
or
um you know maybe lose your job or
whatever it is like if you I mean it's
so easy to be homeless really it's like
like you said like we're two paychecks
of being being one of those people you
know and maybe that hurts to look at but
that is the truth of it and so I think
yeah totally there's ways that we could
focus our our resources and our our help
and our attention on helping more of a
majority than the extreme edges I think
that's totally right I like how you said
that yeah yeah and and so in the city of
Kelso we're moving forward with a
low-income housing project
um it is an 18 million dollar project so
pretty significantly more than uh 3.6
million dollars but it's it's uh
it's geared towards helping the uh
it's it's gonna be 50 of the elderly
population and the other 50 is
classified disabled people
um and it's that's going to be managed
by the housing opportunities for
Southwest Washington and Lower Columbia
CAP which are two organizations that
focus on uh on the people that we're
talking about you know not necessarily
the in your face hey we pitched a 10 on
the front doors of City Hall it's
focusing on the the moms and kids that
are down on their life
and it's focusing on the uh the people
that uh actually want the help that are
just down on their left and
I think that's really important the the
a lot of the cost of that build is
actually because it's going to be above
our new library and uh our new community
center so we're we're mixing uh kind of
a Community Asset with our library and
Community Center with trying to engage
um the people that use our facilities
with the inquila's homeless population
um
interesting yeah I mean yeah what what
did um yeah thanks for thanks for
exploring that with me I mean I needed
such a the whole homeless thing is such
a uh it's a tough conversation it's hard
to know like where where to go with it
what's wrong or right um and then
there's also this arch of of uh you know
feeling like you're saying the wrong
things or not treating these people as
people because of course they're people
but
um I think that sometimes we can get a
little bit overly eggshell stepping on
that sort of thing we don't have real
discussions that we need to have so
those are always good I'm always a fan
of hearing of those so let's go my head
is always using this analogy I think I
heard on a TED Talk years ago and it
kind of it's kind of stuck with me but
um
you know there's there's various jobs of
different people you know I think
different people serve well in different
areas there is so say the analogy that I
that I'm talking about that I got from
the Ted Talk is
say we have a stream in floating down
the stream you're on the shore and you
see you know young people they're
drowning like they need help they need
to get out of the water and you're
seeing them floating in and then like
your first initial instinct is jump in
the water bring them to shore get them
out of the water but then you know you
get them to the shore and then you look
up and there's more people coming
Downstream there's more there's more
kids you know that are um you know in
these kids in this analogy or homeless
people or people with mental health
issues or whatever whatever
um you you're continuously like jumping
in to save them right here because you
can reach them but at some point you got
to go all right what's going on why are
these kids falling in the river why are
they falling like let's walk Upstream
what's going on why are these people in
the river in the first place that they
need to be lifeguarded
um and so that's I guess we can air into
the the conversation about mental health
um you know like why why are people
falling into the river in the first
place like what is I mean I get like
this isn't a huge part of your you know
day-to-day job but just you you as a
person and like what you think about and
you know I know you well because so I
feel like you probably have like a
valuable opinion in this but um I don't
know what what do you think about mental
health like what is it as a whole like
why would someone how do we get homeless
how do we get to where we're
um you know addicted to drugs like what
what is it what can we do better as
small and large communities and just as
individuals I guess
um
um you know I'm not I'm not giving you a
specific question to answer here Keenan
but I guess just the mental health
question as a whole like what what do
you think about it like what's going on
with our with our world here with this
that's the uh I think
uh impulsivity plays a huge role
um
and and I think like we talked about
with the tick tock discussion that uh I
think some of the impulsivity stems from
uh
people being reactionary
um and so it's I think that's kind of
carried over into the public life and I
could be totally off base but
um from what I've seen you know working
with
um
working with people that were convicted
or that are convicted felons in my prior
life
what I noticed is that they're really
impulsive
um it was it was
you know they didn't decide to just
uh I don't I don't know how to explain
this but uh there's something in their
in their mentality in their brain that
that made them into a an impulsive
person and some of that probably does
stem from past dramas
um but man that's a that's a tough
tough question I I gave you an
impossible question of course okay well
what okay so let me ask you this have
you have you ever had an intrusive
thought Keenan do you know what an
intrusive thought is absolutely I think
we all have yeah um so you know I think
I think years ago when I first kind of
started having intrusive thoughts I was
like afraid of myself I'm like oh my God
am I evil like why would I think that
who thinks of that oh my God but you
know then you start doing a little bit
of research you start having
conversations with people you start
learning a little bit about your own
self and your mind and you gain some
mindfulness for me like meditation and
stuff really helped for me but you start
learning like oh I'm Not My Thoughts oh
okay like it's okay to have uh to have
those things like come about like it's
not that abnormal to
it's it's not that abnormal to have
a strange thought like here's an example
this is going to be like hopefully
nobody takes this and clips just this
but like dude you can be holding
someone's baby and the [__] across your
mind of like I could throw this baby
pretty far
you know what I mean like cool let's be
real about it it's not that I'm actually
gonna throw a baby but it's actually you
know some people
um you know and maybe someone listen to
this maybe they've never been aware of
their intrusive thoughts maybe they've
never had intrusive thoughts and that's
cool but there is an actuality of we
just have weird thoughts and they're um
you know they're they stem from
a lot of the things we consume um they
stem from like not having peace they
stem from
um you know our there's a lot of humans
are very intricate you know we have
ourselves figured out in a lot of ways
but also you know like where do ideas
come from I don't know what I'm gonna
what I'm about to say next I'm not
planning it you know I'm just trying to
be the filter of the person who has
thoughts and then says them in in in
real lived reality so
um I mean I think
it's it's when we could face those
things and we could see those
imperfections of just being part of The
Human Experience within ourselves it
gives us a little bit of compassion for
other people of like oh man they are
really at the mercy of those intrusive
thoughts they're really at the mercy of
of those thoughts um of thinking less of
themselves and then we have these ego
protections that kind of like
um you know you know come about in in in
place of thinking those things because
we think that we're bad when we have
these intrusive thoughts um but so from
someone who is like
you know I've had my own struggles with
mental health and all these things
you know getting a wedge between
a thought in your reaction or a thought
in your response to it is a superpower
you know there really is something you
you talked about impulsivity
impulsivity is having no distance
between you and your thoughts there is
no Observer of what's going on and going
oh oh I don't need to react on that oh I
don't need to say that thing oh I feel
this emotion in my body oh I'm actually
angry right now well I know that making
an angry reaction isn't going to benefit
the future of my life or my community or
my loved ones or my friends or the
people around me so let's take a second
take a step back um so I mean I don't
know I I think
if there's some sort of I mean I don't
know is is there like mindfulness
courses we could offer to to homeless
people in in convicts and did you see
any sort of was there when you were
working
um uh around the police force stuff and
then the law enforcement stuff did you
um uh
is there any like meditation classes or
mindfulness or is that a discussion at
all
so with the Department Corrections it
wasn't necessarily meditation or
mindfulness but the treatment uh the
treatment programs were were fairly
plentiful the options were there the
trick was giving the people to
join and stick with equipment options
um and you can
enforce or you can you can require some
of that through their judgment and
sentences but
you know I I don't know how to kind of
change some of these mentalities to
drive that wedge in between their uh
their reactions and their uh yeah they
kind of have to want it right right and
and I think
um in my opinion what I have seen the
more successful people
um have kind of stepped out of their
milieu and into a new area and that's
been more successful than anything so
um this the Washington uh the state of
Washington has a
has a kind of an obscure law where um
you have to return to your county of
origin
um so when you release from prison you
return to the county where you committed
your first felony
um not back to the community that
you might be more successful in and it
was fairly difficult to transfer
somebody from
their County of origin back to where
they might be more successful so I would
literally have people that would have
gone from supervision
because walking down the street they
were going past their dope dealer's
house and it gave them that sense of
urgency to use again so getting them out
of this out of their environment that
[Music]
um
contributed to their addiction was was
fairly successful in my experience
um but you know from the law enforcement
standpoint from the parole and probation
I don't want to use law enforcement
because people assume I was a police
officer I was a parole and probation so
I was about
half uh half treatment and half
enforcement
um so getting people
out of the environment that they
um
that contributed to their addiction was
really important
yeah yeah I think that is valuable and
do we have ways do we have ways of of
doing that in the future like do you see
any sort of Route out of the way that
we're doing that like do you think
because it sounds like it's not super
helpful for them to have to go back to
where they first
you know you know they're released and
they're like all right cool let's like
let's get my life back on track that
sort of thing I mean dude even just
everybody who's listening has probably
moved a couple times in their life even
just moving across town is expensive as
heck dude like it's not it's not easy to
to move and like you really start start
a structure let alone like when you've
been incarcerated for a while
yeah well in the why I call that law
obscure um so I actually had a case
where uh a person was driving from uh
Kelso Longview area to Yakima they're
not to Yakima through Yakima to the uh I
think they were heading to the
Ellensburg area and for people who don't
live in Washington it's uh it's about a
four hour drive
um and over a mountain range uh and he
was popped for marijuana things when he
was 18 years old in this in the uh in
Yakima which is dead center of
Washington State
uh and so at the time that was a felon
um it was a felony violation of the
uniformis controlled substance act he
was 18 years old fresh out of high
school and was just driving to visit a
uh another city
in route to that location
um he was pulled over and arrested for
marijuana and charged with felony he was
convicted of that felony uh I think it
was 25 30 years later approximately
he committed another felony um he had
fallen on Hard Times uh got into dope
um
it was arrested for dope and then uh
served I think uh served just over a
year he was he was uh convicted and
served 366 days or something like that
in state prison when he released because
he had committed his first felony in
Yakima County even though his old base
and his whole family was uh in a
different area he released from prison
to Yakima County where he knew nobody
because he committed his first felony
and so it's it's a little bit odd it
kind of plays a sticky game we we did we
were ended uh able to transfer him back
to a different to to the area that
suited them better where he had that
support group but
um it was kind of a bureaucratic process
for no reason I mean Common Sense would
say hey release him to where his family
is yeah
but the way the laws written we couldn't
yeah that's that is very tricky I mean
I'm sure there's plenty of ways that
like you know maybe I just don't know
that are reasonable to to release them
back to that same spot but
um yeah on the surface I mean how many
we're just ignoring useful information
how many studies is there about you know
the thing with um have you heard the
studies of like rats in a cage and you
give them like a slow
um like drip of crack or drip drip of
some sort of drugs or whatever
um it's it's essentially like if you
alienate them from their community in in
the other rats they're going to
continuously if they're alone they're
going to continuously go and hit that
that they want that drug they're going
to get that drug drip that's in the cage
but if you put them back with the
community they actually will end up
ignoring it like if you put
um I'm totally ruining this study so I
want you to look it up for their own but
uh if you put like just regular water
right here and then right next to it is
water with like some sort of drug in it
when they're alone they're going to
continuously hit that one with the drug
because like it's like they're unhappy
you know whatever but if you introduce
community in their family and stuff back
to them you know you know the rat homies
they're going to eventually realize okay
I feel terrible when I hit that drug
water one but I know I need water
they're just gonna hit the water one
again somebody else look this up because
I totally just butchered that study but
it really is a it's just a reflection of
who we are man as as people as humans uh
we need Community we need each other
it's it's how how we belong you know
it's all it's it's like
yeah getting people alone and alienated
from their friends and family and people
who could support them and people who
could help them get back on their feet
when they're on on hard times it's it's
a big deal you know we need each other
and I don't think that should be ignored
for homeless people who have like made a
few mistakes in their life you know like
they they also need one another and I
think the longer we alienate them
um I mean this this could turn into a
whole stupid conversation of of our
whole prison system really but
um yeah I I just think we need each
other you know and we need to understand
that as much as we need each other as
people who have jobs and we make our car
payments and you know we're not homeless
so so you know we must be doing really
well those those are also people who who
need each other too you know they they
need their family just as much as we do
they're just humans too so well and I'm
I'm glad you went that uh that way with
the study because I think you can
attribute that to to my life
uh as an elected as an elected
um creating that sense of community that
uh that pride in the community uh can
seriously take a dent out of the mental
health and uh and drug addiction issues
you know having that having that pride
in our area
um and I think you get back to that
sense of community by by cleaning up you
know go by doing the basics
um you know right now
and it might be a little bit off of it
on a tangent but right now 60 of our
street lights are
um
they're the not not LED lights so
there's no light in that neighborhood
giving them a sense of Pride
um and also obviously the obvious
lighting up the uh lighting up the
streets better will be a huge crime
reduction method but um we just had a
huge long debate and it actually turned
into more or less a political fight over
uh a park in South Kelso so South
council is historically been our uh
lower income neighborhood so we have
North and South Coastal are kind of our
lower lower income neighborhoods
um we have a park smack dab in the
middle of South Kelso uh
The Proposal initially started as a as
hey you know let's let's fix the park
um and obviously that's the necessary
action that our Council needs to take
um but then the the conversation morphed
uh so one of uh the other council
members that I sit on the on the board
with um
she said hey you know why not do this
park
the right way from the beginning since
we have to replace it anyways and the
standard Across the Nation that we're
seeing is fully Ada accessible parks
um and it's a fantastic idea
um but we have a lot of vandalism in our
Parks so balancing the vandalism with uh
replacing the that critical
infrastructure and uh obviously the
fully Ada auction is going to be
exorbitantly more expensive
um instead of just replacing the park
with 1950s technology let's replace it
with a better full Ada option and then
that will facilitate uh giving the South
Kelso neighborhoods some pride on their
park and help that Community aspect of
it so
the uh the political fight over the cost
uh took place at our last meeting and uh
ultimately we voted on moving forward
with the full Ada option
um but you know when you talk about
community and drinking from that uh
drinking from water infused of crack and
drinking regular water you know giving
them that sense of Pride and in a a
piece of infrastructure with smack dab
in the middle of their neighborhood I
trust that this South Coast neighborhood
is going to police itself in
um taking care of that partner
um because it does give them that sense
of Pride you know I I you were around in
the Longview days when Colony Park uh
the skate park was uh kept getting
graffiti and so their solution to
graffiti in the park was to graffitiate
themselves with art
and that
gave the skateboarders and the excuse I
think is the scooter gang
um at the time it gave them that sense
of Pride and uh in the Clooney Park in
the skate park and now
um they self-police it they don't yep
you know you don't see the graffiti that
we used to yeah yeah we do I actually
really like that you use that example
you know I grew up as a skateboarder you
know it's uh you know managed local
skate shops and stuff when I was younger
and the there is a sense like like if
you're a skateboarder you know it very
well but there is like a you know if you
if you go to the skate park and you try
to leave your food or you litter or
something around one of the local skate
park guys they're gonna grab you by
their shirt and go pick that [__] up
dude it's there is a sense of pride in
let's take care of our stuff and I
really like that they did that that they
worked with you know instead of like you
know posting a police officer up and
checking everyone's bags for for spray
spray paint cans it's like all right
let's let them tag it let's let them
make it beautiful tag though not just
like you know uh you know skeeto was
here or you know like whatever our like
you know Chad loves Janet or you know
just our like sloppy sort of like you
know crackhead graffiti or something for
that's probably a mean ass way to phrase
it but
um yeah there is a way that we could
spray paint our parks and paint our
parks in in a way that's cool you know
and something that we take pride in and
I really like that I think that that is
a a cool way of a cool example of
community is local skate park people you
know anybody listening who's ever been
to a skate park or been a part of those
there is kind of this
like we don't need you know we don't
need the big guys to come down with
their shirts and ties and tell us not to
litter like we got this under control
we're proud of our park and we're going
to keep it that way and you know when
when the the older kids who the young
kids think are cool are doing that sort
of thing the young kids grow up and they
they repeat that same sort of stuff you
know and so if someone leaves their
wrapper they leave their Mountain Dew
can laying out it's like hey man throw
that in the garbage before you leave you
know I think that that's a cool example
of kind of how a larger Community could
work
you know just say the quiet part out
loud people love spray painting dips on
everything yeah
yeah dude actually it's super bad I have
a problem that 10 of all people have I
like to draw dicks dude that scene that
scene is unmatched that scene is really
funny in that movie like like just a
very elaborate like all these
that's too good I haven't watched that
one in a while but um yeah I mean
actually after this podcast so that's
that's my plan I'm gonna go spray paint
some dicks around Austin so you know
it's amazing and that's the uh that's
kind of a funny uh funny topic from City
Life uh you've noticed that you know
when people have issues with potholes uh
they go spray paint a dick around it and
it makes the city react so quickly that
they fix the bottle
yeah that's extra smart
I mean well it's beneficial
it they did get it fixed what what's it
that what's the saying uh you know we
would use it in the mill often was the
squeakiest wheel gets gets the grease
you know and there there is some of that
you know it's uh that's not that
shouldn't always be the case and you
know those are what should draw our
attention to at that moment and but um
there there is something about that like
hey pay attention to this because
there's a big old dick on it you don't
want your you don't want your daughter
to walk by a big old spray painted dick
do you uh but it was funny because in
the city along
it's been pretty underserved and
underrepresented uh there was a massive
pothole and somebody took their full
Christmas tree and stuck it right in the
middle of it and anchored It To The
Ground
there the next day not only take the
Christmas tree but also replace it or
fix the pile
um was it Mark Robbins Christmas tree
no he
looked yeah no well he probably actually
set his Christmas tree on fire in his
backyard too
yeah I guess I can't we can't can't
point fingers yeah we had lots of fun
okay what's a
um something that I'm aware of as I get
older is
um you know and maybe even just like
having some distance from from my
hometown is like I I just love it so
much I really you know I I have the
great opportunity to grow up there and
so I really know the community in and
out now you know I know the names of the
back roads and I know who lives on this
and I know this person Grandpa owns this
store you know like I know like the
hometown feel of it but I think just
like the appreciation for a community
the appreciation for um like you know
the the pretty parts of of Longview and
Kelso both like dude Lake Sacagawea is
crazy beautiful it's so it's underrated
how cool that place is to me um every
time I come and visit her I have work
and work in town I like the first thing
I do in the morning is I go run around
like Sacagawea
um what do you
do you feel that as you get older just
as an adult
um and obviously like you you know your
jobs you're focused on it but do you
find that you uh appreciate your
hometown more um you know not just the
beautiful things but just all the little
intricate little cool things about it
that's uh that's why I moved back so I
had the opportunity when I graduated
I'll stay in Ellers I graduated
from Smackdown
Center of Washington state I had the
ability to stay there
um and I opted to move back because
that's not home to me
um and as I'm getting older so it is
kind of tough to weed out through the
the drama of political life
um where everything is a constant fight
and constant bickering and uh you're
wrong no you're wrong mentality
um and just it it's it's tough to take a
step back and say hey
okay here's here's here's our beautiful
areas in Kelso uh Longview longview's
gorgeous I talked about it uh I talk
about the homeless um homeless issues
but they're
you know their Library the Monticello
Hotel their post office their the Civic
Circle Lake Sacagawea
it's it's almost unmatched how there's
kind of a
they pay homage to the history of the
city while you know taking care of their
streets and parks and and beautification
in the city and same with the city of
Kelso we have a historic downtown area
we have a beautiful train station
um and uh
you know taking that step back and
saying hey our area is
you know unmatched
um with how awesome it can be and the
potential that it has and you know the
the things that we do have that are
beautiful it it is a little tough to
take a step back um but I'm learning
um but by Nature being in the Public
Public eye uh I hear more of the
negativity and the drama than uh
sure
yeah yeah yeah your job forces you to
focus on like the you know the bum fight
outside the train station and not the
beautiful part of the train station you
know I I totally get that but I I just
do think that there's um there's
something to be said you know as a young
as a young person I think that I was
very um you know I was like a you know I
like punk rock and skateboarding and you
know like there was kind of this like
everything sucks sort of vibe in a lot
of ways but as I got older you know I I
gained more more appreciation for the
beautiful sides of things and like how
man it's it's
this this all takes a lot of work you
know it takes a lot of community it
takes a lot of you know really all it
takes is like what if every what if one
person a day like all right we all get
to litter once a day everyone once a day
every single day it's like slowly really
very quickly your place is going to be
filled with garbage you know and so
there's these certain things of taking
pride in your city taking pride in where
you're from
um you know to you know maybe as as
you're walking and you see somebody
litter you know maybe don't be a Karen
of some sorts but there is a way that's
okay to go hey bro not cool pick that
[__] up you know that that sort of thing
they're just a a pride that can um that
can be very truthful as we get older
um you know I I mean I'm only 31 but I
I don't know I feel like
just my comparison to who I was as a
young kid where I'm like Kelso sucks
there's nothing to do you know there's
it's always raining you know it's like
whoa maybe the rain sucks because I had
holes in my shoes or something but
overall the rain you know makes the
beautiful Greenery in the other Seasons
so yeah I don't know I I love pointing
out the appreciation for
um just how awesome our our place is
back there and also like dude we're
smack dab in the middle of like there's
big cities to either side without that
far we can go to the coast we can go to
the mountains we could go to the beach
like you know you can drive a few a few
hours south and and be like you know in
Northern California not very far and you
know it's really is is a wonderful place
and there is Downstream effects of
taking pride in where you're from
so that's actually a pretty famous
criminological theory that I learned
open Windows theory about
uh you know when when a building has a
bro it's gonna kind of facilitate that
mentality that hey it's okay to have
other broken windows and that's what
deteriorates a full neighborhood
um and you're absolutely correct we're
one hour from Mount St Helens uh which
is a very famous volcano that erupted
but it's absolutely gorgeous there's
hiking there's whatever you want to do
we're one hour from the beach uh we're
one hour from Portland which uh
negative uh
negative implications aside is a
beautiful city and we're two and a half
hours from Seattle I mean whatever we
want to do we have almost
immediate access to go do it
um and so that's I love that we're kind
of
um
for you know not only are downtowns
beautiful in Kelso among you but we're a
hub for being able to go and explore and
do whatever we want here and and Reign
aside I you know I I don't mind it um it
gets a little draining towards the end
of the rainy season but
I'm pretty well acclimated to it yeah
yeah well uh yeah I mean I mean it's
funny I find myself as I'm explaining
you know I'll be showing pictures of my
favorite hikes or something to people
that I meet as as I'm traveling you know
here in Austin or you know I travel for
work too so I'll be telling people about
these hikes or showing them pictures and
stuff and that is always the things like
well doesn't it rain there all the time
like yes it does and you know it does
suck and there is you know like the
seasonal depression thing is a very real
thing for many people you know even you
know from a levels of vitamin D's and
the ways it affects our hormones and
that sort of things is very real but
there's also there is a there is a high
that I'll tell people about like yo if
it's if eight months of rain and stuff
once it hits summer
like everyone is in such a great mood
because we've all been through it
together that that summer is so fun it's
so beautiful everything is utilized so
well everyone's outside every day
um yeah there is um I mean there's
there's good and bad with anything but I
think that
um you know allowing the you know more
often
rainy season to define the entirety of
the area is is foolish you're really
missing out on some really awesome
Summers and springs and stuff over there
yep and and you're right though what do
we do all uh all summer now we go sit on
a boat
when I leash we uh you know have have a
couple a couple of beers um just one or
two though never more um and we go have
a good time
and it's it you're right the the high
that you get from the summer makes the
winner
worth it yeah yeah absolutely I'm uh I'm
uh being in Austin for a few years like
I enjoy it I like being in the city I'm
like 10 minutes from the main downtown
you know I'm kind of I'm really close to
everything
um and I love it so much but I think
that I am learning I might be more of a
small town cold weather kind of guy like
you know
I'll tell you what I know is as often as
I you know I've worked at warehouser for
five years and as much as I was like
this doesn't Define me and this isn't me
and I need to get out and I'm an artist
not like poetry and like all this stuff
it's also like oh that's actually a huge
part of who I am as I also like that
other stuff and that's okay too you know
like I like Romeos aren't so bad you
know
how much fun did you have
getting blasted with mud on a side by
side or an Old Logging Back Road dude my
face hurt you know what's so funny is uh
yeah yeah no it really my face
legitimately hurt from laughing like
that was such a such a wonderful time
yeah Keenan's referring to last time
that I was that I came home um
um our our good friend Mark has a side
by side and so is four of us in there
and uh just cruising through the old
back roads like dude you can't get that
like that's a you you can't do that in
every city in America you know that's a
that's a really specific thing that we
get to have is just mobbing through the
woods laughing with your friends you
know we have the music playing we're
getting stuck in the mud it was freezing
cold but amazing it was it was so fun
that was actually like a that was so
fulfilling for me man I feel like that
that lasted for a couple weeks for me
yeah oh yeah it's it's always uh always
a good time and then the scenery when
you get up there a lot of people don't
uh appreciate the fact that when you
Crest the hill
um up on an Old Logging Road you'd look
out and there's just miles and miles and
Acres of trees
um and it's just absolutely it's it's
breathtaking you can't even explain it
your pictures don't do it justice
um but it's it's such an awesome feeling
to be able to just look over a valley
over the tops of all these trees and it
we're in a great area up here yeah it's
it's unmatched I'm I'm sure anybody
who's from the area listening is
complete in a complete agreeance like we
don't really have to say it but it is
funny that I notice uh I'll have I'll
make new friends that live in Austin or
you know they live in places where it's
uh you know more flat and and less less
nature in their lives and they'll
literally send me videos or something
from reels or Tick Tock of uh like these
beautiful places that we went to when we
were kids and teenagers and they're like
bro could you imagine is this even real
I'm like oh yeah I've been there and
they're like what you know and of course
the video you know really sells it it
has filters and effects and good music
so it sounds extra exciting but or even
um uh you know the gorge you know the
one of the most incredible music venues
that any of us
you're going tomorrow wait what what
what uh oh Watershed is tomorrow
whatever
oh wow cool dude that's so fun uh yeah
Watershed for anybody listening is a big
country music festival Keenan has gone
many times
um Keenan's if you're wondering Keenan's
taste in music is also unmatched uh
Keenan and I have been friends for very
long and that's something that we've
always bonded over is is music so uh
don't be afraid to hit him up for a song
selection or a playlist recommendation
for sure what's um what's your plan for
watershed this year are you guys doing
like gold camping or what what's uh and
who's playing actually so we have kojo
um Cody Johnson
and the the Friday night uh lineup is
fairly light but then uh
I'm most excited to see Cody Johnson on
Friday night but then there's Keith
Urban Luke Bryan uh Cameron Marlow
Laney Wilson
um
you like her don't you lady good old
Laney Wilson yeah for obvious reasons
um no and uh
I don't I don't even miss I've gone so
many times and I've seen most of the
artists um and I don't even follow the
lineups anymore because it's just a a
weekend to decompress and get away
um other than last year where it was 110
degrees and I felt like I was melting
all weekend uh yeah uh and no shade
um yeah but we camp in Premiere
um it's just myself and my girlfriend
going this year but we're meeting up
with uh so I think seven years ago we
ended up camping next to a group of
Canadians and they brought like 30
people they had you know multiple
campsites
um they brought 100 foot slip and slides
about eight pools
um and we camped next to them and they
adopted me for the second time in my
life I was adopted uh and
uh so we've been friends ever since and
we meet up and they still bring the slip
inside I think there's 12 of them going
uh this year the same continuance of
friends that I've met from a music
festival seven years ago that we're
still friends with today and all uh I've
been up to Canada once but uh went up
and met up with them and hung out with
them uh in the off season uh outside of
watershed but man the lifelong
friendships that you make for music
festivals in any genre music and it's
it's remarkable
yeah no no it absolutely is I also grew
up going to music festivals and stuff
I've never been to Watershed it's always
been one we talked about I'm like I
would love to go I you know I I don't
listen to a ton of country
um but I like a lot of country
um I I mean just with music in general I
like more than I dislike with pretty
much anything unless it's Yeah by Usher
I hate that song Still
um but uh uh yeah dude
and dude yeah cupid shuffle all of it
it's terrible get better taste in music
people listen to a new song
um but uh yeah dude the the the
friendships and just like the
the openness to new people I mean at a
music festival it's this it's this thing
that you wouldn't do anywhere else like
you're all there for the same reason you
all have you know already you have
something in common with these people
like hey we all like music or we're all
um you know for the most part we're here
to have a good time this weekend and so
it just drops these boundaries you know
and you can create um again to reuse the
word Community to create little
communities around you of uh people who
are enjoyable uh people who enjoy the
same things as you and so yeah there's a
lot of openness there's a lot of
connection that I've had at music
festivals that um
uh you know I I
I I've spent a lot of time in like the
electronic music festival world and so
there is this uh plur peace love unity
respect and I know it's like silly and
it has this like dorky thing but it
really is you know there is music
festivals and shows where when that's
alive you can really feel it and it is
this accepting thing um but you know
even metal shows dude like there is
something you'll hear the person on the
stage say hey when someone gets knocked
down what do we do and everybody goes
pick them the [__] up you know like
there is a there's a at festivals it's a
good example of of togetherness you know
and I I really like that and so it's
cool to see that um they're still doing
shows there and you know because we
recently had uh that there was a
shooting at the Gorge a few months back
at an electronic music festival and uh I
I would just hate for you know one one
bad actor who's bringing a weapon into
this thing to to paint or alter the
future of
um you know the beautiful nature of of
music festivals and stuff so
do your best to attend the show there I
know it's it's near Quincy Washington
which nobody in their life has heard of
or George Washington
um is out in the middle of nowhere
overlooks so the venue when you're
standing on the top of the hill so it's
it's an Amphitheater that with a very
steep uh grass hill when you're standing
at the very top and you overlook the
Columbia River um the Columbia River
Gorge and the bend in the river uh just
over the uh over the stage it's
it's phenomenal I remember the first
time I stopped was actually for a
Christian music festival where I was
working security
um I walked up over the hill and I
crested the hill and it might it took my
breath away it was amazing no yeah I
mean you've quite literally once you see
it you you realize oh I've quite
literally never seen anything like this
I mean just the the fact that this stage
is right on the edge of that giant
Canyon it gives it this crazy depth and
uh I mean a sunset there is is wild and
they usually do really well of timing
whoever's playing on that Sunset slot to
be a a good fit for it it seems like
everyone is pretty aware of that so
that'll be super fun man I hope you guys
have a really good time
um and I've noticed artists uh
they perform better
at the Gorge versus you know the stadium
tour and so it's uh I mean you'll see
the best uh so I was I've seen Tim
McGraw play
I've probably seen five or six times
live uh you know one of my hobbies is
going to concerts in general
um and not just country concerts but
when I saw him at the Gorge probably my
most memorable
time at the Gorge the sun was going down
he sat on the edge of the stage in his
T-shirt that said that so they call us
shutters when you go to Watershed uh he
he wore his T-shirt that said shedder
um and he's saying live like you're
dying and actually he didn't sing it
towards the end of the song the whole
crowd sang it right as the sun was going
down it's probably my most memorable
moment with him just sitting I mean he
he had tears on his eyes just from the
experience it was it was amazing dude
I'm getting chills just for you talking
about it because I just know how those
moments go they really are they're just
uh transcendental in in a way they
really are are magical dude have you
heard of the I don't think that I texted
it to you maybe I did have you heard of
the caverns in Tennessee
[Music]
oh my gosh okay so after this you got to
look it up but um it's it's basically an
underground concert venue like it's a
cave it's a cave but you you do I think
they do quite a few electronic shows
there and stuff um it's uh I mean dude I
think it almost I haven't I actually
have not been to Red Rocks yet either I
haven't um I've been there as an
attendee or ever worked a show there but
I like it's at the top of my list of
course but I'm almost thinking that the
caverns is like flirting with with uh
you know the uh Red Rocks
um you know with my desired wanting to
go there so you'll have to look that up
afterwards or listeners just look up the
caverns in um Tennessee it's very
interesting as the gorgeous
the other Gorge puts it to shame yeah
see I've heard that from many people I I
think that I have such a connection to
the gorge and I've had so many good
times with so many good friends and so
many memories um one is interesting as
you get older like the amount of times
that I've been singing side by side arm
around somebody at the Gorge you know
and then you I mean like I've literally
like lost friends who aren't with us any
longer and I but I've shared those
moments with them at the Gorge and now
it has this like extra beauty that I
didn't know could be tapped into from
that moment so it really is something
special anybody listening definitely go
to anything at the Gorton honestly like
I mean you know
don't move there keep it precious but
also the the Pacific Northwest is just
so great yeah I mean Kelso and Longview
is really cool Castle Rock Woodland
Kalama it really is is an unmatched
unmatched place you know as someone like
I you know we've seen the the intricate
insides of it by growing up there and
being around there but um I think just
even outside of that even just as a
newcomer it's just such a cool awesome
place it really is when's the last time
you've been through Castle rocks
downtown
it's been a couple years
uh go uh so they they focused on a
program called the communities in bloom
program
where every single light pole has a
absolutely stunning hanging Flower
Basket on it yeah and the way that they
set up that it's Castle Rock Washington
and every time you Google it it comes up
like Castle Rock Colorado it's not even
on Google
um Castle Rock Washington's at the base
of Mount St Helens of the road to get up
to Mount St Helens and they're downtown
they're downtown beautification efforts
are
um it's they literally won awards from
them so next time you're up here just
drive through downtown Castle Rock and
that's that's what we for the first time
in my life I feel like this or in in the
city of Kelso's history we're trying to
copy them uh nice because they have done
so good at their downtown beautification
efforts yeah yeah yeah well so I
actually got to live the um uh you'll
remember my house in in Castle Rock we
lived there for five years and uh dude I
fell in love with that place like uh we
we were lucky enough to live close
enough to where you know I could I
didn't have to get in my car for
anything like I walked to the grocery
store walked to the post office every
day and yeah you just even back then uh
it's been a few years now even back then
it was very beautiful they were really
good about
um uh the flowers and the beautification
and like there's always somebody out
there watering it and I also love the
you know the time of year they would um
uh based on the time of year they're
playing like themed music from this from
the speaker polls you know not super
loud or intrusive but just like you know
it's Christmas time so we've got a
little Christmas music playing in the
downtown area and that's so that's so
sweet man that's I love that
yeah yeah it's a small town feel and I
think they have public Wi-Fi throughout
the whole city now um yeah I mean to me
that's like not only are they uh
a beautiful downtown they have public
Wi-Fi everywhere
like that's that's cool yeah yeah
especially for a small town you know
it's kind of a um I don't know if we're
allowed to say this anymore but it's I
feel like it's kind of a hick town like
a I mean that's what it seemed like when
we were in uh high school anyway that
always seemed like the the guys with mud
all over their trucks that came to
school at Kelso like that they lived in
Castle Rock you know they had their own
section of the parking lot so you know
that's that's how it was
um
well cool man um we're we're getting up
here in time I mean you know no rush of
course was there anything um at the
Forefront of your mind that you wanted
to make sure that that we mentioned or
anything that any Loops that you may
have opened up that you wanted to close
or anything of the sorts but well I do
you know we had a couple questions on
and I'm happy to happy to answer them if
uh now's the appropriate time yeah yeah
so there was a question about why is the
Cydia can also closed on Fridays
um and we were faced with you know
obviously since we're a smaller
Community to our neighboring City uh we
were faced with losing employees
because the City of Longview is on four
tens and they pay more so they got a
higher wage and a better schedule uh and
so it was just last year the city opted
to as a as a method of employee
retention and employee happiness to be
blunt we closed uh closed our city hall
on Fridays I mean we gave we give
everybody a three-day weekend
it was more about uh
you know keeping our employees happy and
so uh yeah it's a it's an inconvenience
for Citizens at times because it's you
can't pay your bills uh in person on
Fridays but
um we have actually retained more
employees
um and and not lost some of our
employees to higher paying jobs because
we're closed on Fridays so it's a
decision like you're aware that it is an
inconvenience for the people but it was
a decision that you're that is for the
employees that are working there that's
that's what you're saying and that
wasn't a council action I think I
explained to you a little bit um so from
from a council perspective we don't
um
you know we're more legislative uh
legislative
um and we're more
uh you know policy procedure budget uh
law uh and so our city manager obviously
told us about it as he as he should uh
but uh that wasn't an action Council
took that's really a management
um an upper level City management role
um to determine what's best for the
employees obviously with respect to
um the citizens because we are elected
and we're gonna we're gonna take the
brunt of the of the heat for those
decisions but
um it made all the financial sense
because you know retraining employees
losing long-term employees to uh
municipalities that pay more it was
it was a the right decision that's for
sure
oh yeah I mean yeah yeah it makes sense
I could see how it'd be frustrating
though you know I could see how it's
like
um you know the the the commenter um I
think was was pointing out that were
they basically saying that they didn't
have time to
um uh go there because they're working
the four tens or this wasn't an employee
who posted right that was it uh I don't
think so um I don't
he might be uh I don't know
all of the employees at the city of Elsa
but
um so before our city manager takes any
actions like that he has to clear it
with all the unions um all the union
reps make sure it follows all uh proper
procedure make sure the majority of
people agree
um and then he takes that action so you
know I I don't believe this was a an
action that he took willy-nilly or
um as a rash decision I think it was
well thought out
um and it's actually saved from the city
standpoint it's saved us some money
having his doors locked on uh on Fridays
um and you know we're not running as
much power till our just our
city hall building
um just to keep the lights on very
expensive
um and so it saved us money uh obviously
more long-term but it's saved us money
in employee retention employee training
but also electricity and uh keeping the
door shut for one day a week
sure sure yeah yeah I mean there's
something about like uh
trying to save the money for the power
in your building at the expense of me
not being able to go there that does
feel kind of crappy but it sounds like
that's not the only only Factor here you
know it sounds like it's a employee
satisfaction sort of thing too which is
very it's underrated important to keep
to keep the people who work for you
happy and and fulfilled and stuff so
yeah and it takes less than a minute to
pay your utilities
online on the phone we've expanded our
options for uh online pay
um rather than just in person and we
actually have I I don't know if it's
still operational we have a drive
through to pay utility billing too so we
make it pretty convenient uh Monday
through Thursday
um and I think even on the weekends you
can call and pay your Municipal Bill and
our automated system so you know it's
not like there's really ever an
opportunity where you just can't pay and
I know our uh I know our finance
department fairly well um and I know
that they're going to take every
opportunity to
to help our citizens that are
can't necessarily meet our requirements
um and and we'll do everything in their
power to help help people help the
citizens so you know if you're having
trouble my recommendation would be to
reach out to them and have that
discussion yeah yeah cool yeah yeah I
like that yeah so there are some you
know some downfalls but it sounds like
the resources are still there for them
to do what they need to do um there was
also somewhere around that same
conversation
um there was a comment about
um uh the the defend our ranks sort of
position like uh if it feels as a I
would like you to elaborate a little bit
on that just because uh you know I could
see how that would feel frustrating if
you're um you know if there's not an
open discussion or maybe they're they're
not in the right place at the right time
sort of thing of hey I have this problem
but um it feels like the people who are
listening on the council might be like
trying to like shut you down and
defending one another and that sort of
thing and you know we want Solutions
right we want to solve we have a problem
let's solve it together
um and if this commenter um felt that
um they they couldn't get through in in
in in a sense so uh could you elaborate
on that
absolutely because it frustrates the
hell out of me too
um our city uh so our cities the city of
Kelso is really unique and where we're a
charter code city so we are bound by a
charter which is more prohibitive than
the state law so our Charter which was
voted on by our people is oftentimes
more strict than state law and our
Charter runs how we operate
um because we're a charter code city
um with what we call a weak mayor so not
that he's physically weak but he he has
no other power than other members of
council he's not he's not elected as
mayor he's appointed by Council as mayor
and it's basically to run the meetings
um and so in our rules and regulations
um through our Charter and through our
code uh through our Municipal Code our
meetings
um
are are really regimented each person is
three minutes no more
um we our mayor does allow more
flexibility when he can
um for uh or when it's appropriate
um for more than three-minute discussion
but we as Council people cannot debate
um we can't even
we're not even allowed to click our
microphone to raise our hand to debate
with anybody that spoke so our our
meetings
um which follow open public meetings act
but also Roberts Rules of Order for a
charter uh
will not allow even a council member to
speak more than twice on a single issue
so we have to come
very prepared to our meeting and so
that's why we have other
forms of communication that are
made for different dialogues so we have
Workshops the second Tuesday of every
Earth second meeting of every month so
the the third Tuesday of every month we
have a workshop and that's really what
the the public forum for communication
with
um and debate and talk to council
members that's what that meeting is for
because we're not it's a it's a workshop
so we're not bound by the open public
meetings act and we're not prohibited by
our Charter
um and quite literally nobody shows up
to that meeting
um so we have people that will show up
at six o'clock for our regular schedule
meeting where you can't debate but they
won't show up to our meeting just prior
where you can debate
um but I'm also
you know I give out my cell phone number
good
I'm you're afraid man
uh and well that's where the that's
where the hurricane Harvey comment came
from because I
don't know a constituent called and
quite literally chewed me out and told
me I was an f and piece of [__] and uh
blah blah blah blah I think he called me
like uh he called me like a fat whatever
ugly whatever you just chewed me up and
down and then he hung up on me and then
two minutes later he uh posted on
Facebook that it was Hurricane Harvey so
um oh wait is that how the original
origination of the name came yep oh
that's too good I love it like three
weeks ago this was it was a recent all
right recent but you know my cell
phone's always on
um drives my girlfriend nuts uh because
I'll answer the phone at 11 00 p.m uh
midnight I don't really care I tend to
answer more than not
um but I also my emails always open too
and I think the the if somebody has a or
wants to have dialogue
um you know I
I I don't know everything
um uh so I I do the best I can to
research and learn but if I don't know
something I'll respond to the person
that I don't know but I'll find out and
so I'm happy to have that open dialogue
in email phone call um whatever uh so I
I try to make myself as available as
possible
um I I but I hear the frustration
um
that uh
you know the the dialogue at our
physical meetings
um
is is Pretty Tough uh it drives me it
drives me absolutely insane right yeah
um okay well I mean I I guess like I'll
just ask as an interviewer like if you
can make sure that you guys are
pointing people in the right direction
like if they go to the wrong meeting and
try to say the wrong things and you're
like dude I can't even we can't even
talk about this right now like make sure
that they know when when is a good time
to to speak about those things and it
sounds like you guys already do but um
yeah just for anybody listening who
um you know maybe your your responses
and your uh uh the things that you want
to raise are in in good like maybe
they're valuable but just make sure that
they're being uh spoken about in the in
the correct appropriate time so we can
actually get to the bottom of solving
some things and get to some sort of
solutions and because yeah I can
understand how it feel disregarded or
like cool okay this isn't important to
you guys so I guess that we don't get to
talk about it you know that would suck
yeah and our our city
um
municipalities in general can do a
better job of transparency
um it's been something I've tried to
push along the Finish Line since I've
been elected
you know how do we get that message out
there like Hey we're having a workshop
today
um let's see let's put it on Tick Tock
hey we're having a workshop today kids
show up and
um you know I
how do we spread that message better
because we can't so our mayor does uh
will key up his microphone after a
constituent comment and say hey
um I recommend that you speak to the
city manager or a doctor or
well you know we just had a workshop on
this please watch back to well they're
not even recorded anymore
um which drives me nuts as well but uh
you know here's here's who to talk to to
get the information that you need
um so he does have that ability key up
and he'll Point people in the right
direction but um
yeah it's it's it's Uber frustrating
frustrated yeah yeah I can see that but
I mean but dude I think it's cool that
you're you're willing to listen you're
not ignoring I mean it's insane that you
provide your number just publicly for
people to call uh I think you're crazy
for that but I also think that it's
um you know you've also you've never
been afraid of of conflict you've never
been afraid of
um having a conversation that you don't
know the answers to and I really like
that and respect that about you man like
um I I think that
you know humanizing yourself is so okay
especially as like a someone who's on on
a council of like dude you're not just
you know some sometimes I see it where
someone if um you know say I'm in a role
where I'm I'm in a leadership role or
I'm a supervisor or I'm a manager or
something and I'm wearing a collared
shirt it's like immediately they're
trying to talk to me as someone with a
collared shirt rather than like hey
chill man like I like ignore the collar
right now it's not an authority thing
it's a I'm a person who has a job I'm
trying to do the best like really let's
talk here to here you know don't talk at
the image of who you think I'm
representing or don't talk it um the
don't talk to the caller talk to me
right here and I feel like you make that
very accessible and I think that's a
really good thing
I try to be as real
um as real as possible
um you know what I actually hoped for
this interview is that um you know your
listeners can see that hey I'm just a
normal dude like I'll talk about spray
painted dicks like I'll uh I'll have an
open dialogue conversation yes I uh yes
I'm versed on uh Municipal leadership
but also hey I'm just a dude I'm a 33
year old dude that likes cars I like to
go play in the mud uh you know I I will
have a beer or five on weekends like we
are real people uh and you know don't be
like don't put us on the pedestal
um just because we are elected you know
and that's that's been something that
I've been trying to uh the perception
that I've been trying to change with the
community
um is hey we're not a bunch of old white
guys
been in uh
elected for you know 35 years and you
know past policy the same way don't
listen to anybody that's that's the
furthest from the truth and in fact my
uh
so I drew an opponent the selection
cycle
um and he's a few years younger than me
and I I seriously thank him for filing
for office
um and and you know obviously I think
I'm a a better candidate but the the
respect that I have for him willing to
throw his hat in the ring you know just
like we talked about prior
um being a young
um
being a young leader is tough
um and trying to change that perception
has been a hurdle to get over and so I'm
so glad and thankful that I drew an
opponent and it's it's one that I can
stand and shake his hand and respect him
um just simply by throwing his hat with
me like that's so commendable that
anybody's willing to file for public
office you know we're gladness for
punishment it it
you know to what two days ago I'm
thinking like I'm thinking to myself man
this sucks this is I was getting
I was getting [__] thrown at me from
quite literally
sticks different ways
um over uh my vote for an ADA accessible
Park something that I thought hey we can
all hang our hats on hey we're helping
out uh differently abled people
um have access to a park uh and
apparently that was uh Uber offensive
and I was you know here I was thinking I
was doing the right thing
um so the the fact that somebody's
willing to sign up to
take that uh responsibility on is so
commendable
um and I can't respect him more for
doing that the first thing I did was I
messaged hey dude seriously thank you
for reaching out uh let's you know uh if
you ever want to have a coffee if you
ever want to uh sit down and go over uh
whatever you need help with I'm happy to
do that because it's this is not a tough
or it's not an easy position to be
no not not at all yeah yeah I I commend
you for it it's definitely uh uh uh man
I I really like it I think it it seems
so obvious when you talk and it comes
forth of like this um if you're have you
ever heard of uh Simon sinek he's like a
motivational leadership uh speaker
um you may have like stumbled across a
couple of his videos he's been he's all
over the Internet he's actually a
wonderful author I recommend literally
all of his books
um uh but he has this this very popular
thing of start with why and starting
with your why it's like you could handle
any you could handle anyhow you can
handle anything after that start with
why and I feel like if you have a why of
legitimately I love this city and I just
want to make it good I want to keep it
good and I want to make it make it
better and like all this stuff like I
just I just want my my love and passion
for this community that we have to shine
through if that's your why then I think
that that anything that follows and it
is is just truth you know anything that
um you know whether you're in some sort
of debate or conversation where you
don't know all the answers and maybe
you're going to put your foot in your
mouth or you know maybe you'll make a
mistake or maybe you you know you're
human but I think that at the at the
very core if you start with your why of
um I mean I'm gonna sound so overly
obvious and maybe corny but like just
loving where you're from I think that
that that really can solve a majority of
problems or like at least keep everybody
facing the correct direction
well and that's what uh one thing that I
wanted to bring up is uh in this
interview
um you know a lot of people
um kind of they have different copies
you know for me my uh public life is
more or less my hobby
um and I I chase the high of bettering
my community you know some people want
to be uh Instagram influencers I want to
be a public leader in the city that I
love you know that's what I uh
that's what I enjoy doing
um and and so that's why I do what I do
uh more often than not it's thankless
but you know that that motivation to hey
I have the ability to actually affect
change in this small town uh that is
what keeps me
doing what I do
um and it's uh
it's been it's been rewarding but
challenging at the same time
um but this is my hobby
um my hobby is trying to better
um better the city that I thought
yeah yeah that's great I I think it's
apparent and then I think that uh you
know in any conversation that you have
following
um I think that'll will be apparent to
them too you know so I uh I I wish you
the most luck on your on your upcoming
journey and with the election and
everything
um um all that of course I have I have a
random personal question that I was just
thinking like as you're talking about
being a leader and just as someone I I
know uh well I don't know if we've ever
uh discussed this or if your mindset has
changed are you planning on having kids
Keenan
yeah yeah or I mean like what would you
like to have children oh absolutely yeah
yeah I would love
uh nothing more to have a have a us one
of my spawns running around a mini
keenone a little hurricane running
around
no yeah it's the thing that I do have
planned in the future um I want to get
uh my finances my house my uh
my life pretty structured
um before I bring
um I bring a kid into the world I want
to do the traveling I want to do the uh
you know do the life first before I um
try to
influence a little a little human's life
if that makes sense so yeah it isn't it
is something that I I do desire to do I
mean I I hear you and I sound like I'm
um like an old man with gray hair
something who knows something about
something I'm not a father yet either
but um uh dude I think if you had if you
you know if you guys got pregnant
tomorrow I think you'd be just fine man
I think you're I think you're plenty
ready now so
um yeah I I just think that's cool I I
uh I don't know it's just cool to like
I think I spent many years never wanting
to be a kid and I would also come from
the world of um um and it's weird it's
actually like very it's really almost a
selfish position that I realize now of
like I'm not bringing a kid into this
world this world is messed up and that's
stupid dude that's dumb that's some
corny [__] that's um I don't agree with
that now like I I definitely um uh you
know I don't know I I'm the same boat
it's where as much as I didn't want to
when I was younger I'm definitely like
oh yeah I would love to have some kids
and uh you know what I think that I am
worthy of raising a kid who who um you
know could be a good person and blah
blah blah you know that that sort of
thing so did my girlfriend text you and
ask you to have a yeah she's actually
she's on FaceTime right now on the
she's going yes yes uh no no no no no
that's funny I I always love to I always
love to bring that up you know it's it's
cool knowing people for so long and just
seeing how we all change and we grow in
our opinions of these sorts of things
just expand and um you're smirking like
you're like I haven't matured a bit
that's one of the weirdest merch
mentally no
now that I'm running this election cycle
I'm like 100 150 pounds lighter than I
was last I should suck so I have changed
uh yeah yeah you've lost literally a
whole person you know I actually have
fat camp written down in my notes when
did you go to Fat Cam
two years ago no it was kind of funny I
flew to flew to Mexico and had weight
loss surgery and I joke about it being
fat camp but it was a quite literally
one of the most impactful things that
I've done uh
so I didn't realize how uh
how unhappy I was so you know when I
when I first had the weight loss surgery
I was like oh you know I'm just doing
this because I'm tired of people uh
tired of people talking [__] about my
weight whatever
um but now it's like my energy levels my
my happiness is has increased tenfold
and it's like oh okay now I see
um why people are pushing me
um
in the past and so I think you probably
have noticed a change in uh my uh
personal and my happiness uh now than
from back then too you know most people
that listen to your podcast uh probably
don't know but you and I had
disagreements in the past that
um we obviously we've worked through at
this point but um a lot of that stemmed
from my unhappiness so yeah
it was a uh as well as mine yeah the
most impactful thing that I've done and
some people call me crazy because uh I
didn't even really tell anybody I just
kind of flew to Mexico and had them
remove 80 of my stomach
um yeah it's not just some people call
you crazy that's crazy
that's really crazy you want to talk
about impulsivity
yeah yeah you need some mindfulness bro
yeah
that's cool pictures from four years ago
when I was campaigning to now I'm dude I
I looked like like uh but dude I looked
like Shamu's cousin back then man I was
I was
I was large yeah well and and I mean you
can definitely vouch for it like you
just said it's like you don't feel like
yourself I mean you said energy levels
but I think that's like an underrated
that's like almost a casual way of
explaining like you don't there's a
level of you yourself like the
expression of who you are that is being
completely like bogged down by you know
just just being miserable and like just
your body making you feel sick like when
you don't feel when your body doesn't
feel good your mind doesn't think nearly
as clear you know and and you have the
stark contrast of of the before and
after to know like oh wow I really feel
a lot better than I did and I didn't
even I mean it's it's the same thing we
we as humans have
um a fantastic ability to get used to
what's going on to to find Comfort or
find identity in whatever it is that we
are going through and so of course we're
going to want to you know you know
protect that from drastic change and um
you know it's just we could show up as
better versions of ourselves when we're
um you know not carrying around so much
extra extra weight mentally or
physically yeah well and quite literally
I
I no man I can grow dude Queen it's so
so quick on my feet
what's that you think you could beat me
in a foot race oh I don't know I could
try all right next time I come home dude
it's on what people don't understand
that joke but uh
instead of beefing at the bar with
people and getting in a physical
altercation we just tell them to go hey
let's go let's go foot race in the
center of the road and so numerous times
we would clear out a full uh
establishment to watch two two grown men
foot raised on the stuff out of the
street this is a life hack for anybody
listen if you want to like take a little
bit of uh the good juice from a small
community something that you could do is
uh well I will say we've also been in
plenty of fist fights When We Were Young
too like we've definitely uh like just
way too many um but I will say that is a
superpower of I would love to
proliferate proliferate that around
around the world of like next time you
have a beef with someone it could be
very real and you're about to kick each
other's ass
shake your hand or you know you know go
outside challenge each other to a foot
race whoever wins wins whoever loses
loses you shake each other's hands
afterwards and that beef is over Dude a
foot race will solve many problems I
love that
that
completely I have seen it in action
where the two people can be just
absolutely
just angry at each other and one of them
says fine let's go foot race let's go
foot race in the middle of the street
and you I mean everybody goes outside
thinking you're gonna get in a fist
fight and you line up and you sprint
down the middle
it's so funny it's good and it's great
for everybody watching and it also
brings this laughter to it it's like the
energy is almost transmuted into this
like a weird silliness of like man we're
about to fist fight in there that's
crazy
kind of right at the end of things it
kind of just seems like uh well it
probably if we're willing to solve our
beef over a foot race it probably wasn't
worth uh punching each other and
potentially going to jail
no no there's no way
called on us for foot racing uh and they
got an absolute kick out of it uh where
they when they found out the actual
intent behind the foot race uh
they they thought okay now we can get
behind this idea
yeah that's really similar that's some
that's some Millennial [__] right there
somehow that really is like you know as
our older people would go like you know
what back back in my day would go
outside and kick each other's ass we buy
each other a beer afterwards you know
and you know maybe there's something
about that too for sure uh We've
participated in that as well but uh I
like the foot race I feel like that's
very uh that's a very modern way of
solving problems
yeah I remember uh so one thing that
Kelso high school did really well was uh
you'd get in a fist fight you'd help
each other up and you'd shake hands and
the beef would be squashed I mean I
watched somebody throw a guy Through a
Windshield of a car where all cars were
all parked in a circle
um behind the old Safeway and he picked
up somebody threw them through the
windshield of a car helped him out of
the windshield they shook hands on their
friends after that like uh you know so
yeah we've been in our fair share of
altercations but it was always uh always
ended up out of respect
um or not out of respect but it ended up
respectful but it's the same thing
applies to foot racing yeah you know
what's actually funny there must be it's
like a guy thing that we have access to
is like squashing the beef after the
fight I remember I I had to a fist fight
with one of my good friends like we
ended up just like hating each other
over the course of a few weeks we
finally fought a couple times and then
the next day at school I remember like
just beelining right to like no we both
got suspended or something anyway once
it was all over I be lined right to him
he beelined right to me we hugged each
other was like sorry man cool I'm glad
that's over and we're best friends
literally like right away again so it's
just like posted on social media
that was I I would hope that it's not on
social media in any any longer but um
yeah I was probably like what 50 that
was probably like 17 or 16 or something
yeah interesting man yeah what a wild
ride this is isn't it like we you know
just just growing and changing and
evolving and having all these
experiences lead up to like yeah like
suddenly You're A city councilman you
know we're talking about like fist
fighting and stuff when we were in high
school but now you're this um yeah and
you also I mean yeah you brought up that
we have been friends for many years but
we had a lot of disagreements you know
on both sides I think you know you said
you brought up the fact that like you
you were unhappy and weren't feeling
like your best but I was also going
through a lot of my own like
psychological uh mental health stuff
that I was I was at a point where like
any sort of um what I deemed to be
negativity or anything that wasn't
and looking back it's literally what I
needed like I needed just like I mean I
didn't even want to listen to like music
that had cuss words at that point in my
life like I was just very much like I
just really I was I was sick I was I was
really dealing with a lot of depression
stuff I was sick so I was just like I
need to be the uh you know the the
security guard for what's being put into
my mind and what in what's into my
thoughts and my vicinity and so I was
very much like anything that's negative
I ain't having it you know and and a
area that you and I have always like got
along with really well is like we will
disagree for you know we'll disagree but
be both very unafraid to talk about it
you know and so sometimes our
disagreements we'd always end up as
brothers we always love each other and
hug each other at the end but um yeah
you know
um uh you know I'm glad you're in my
life Keenan and I'm glad to know you and
I'm glad that um you know we're able to
to reconnect and we do we both do this
very guy [__] of like we kind of let it
go we don't have to talk about it that
much but it's like yeah I I was wrong in
this way you're wrong in that way but
it's all love you know I I really think
that's cool
that was
that was a year or two wasn't it oh yeah
definitely I mean but you you weren't
you weren't the only one like I mean I
was just I I went Buckwild with some
scissors and I was like out of anybody
who is bringing negativity to my life or
things that aren't um helping my mental
health positively
um I I ain't having you around and so
you know I was just like a bit a bit
extreme with my with my views but I will
say it's it's what I needed and so I'm
glad to have um I'm glad to to have
rekindling and glad to have good friends
still on the other side of all of that
absolutely but yeah I mean but also on
my uh
I I was named uh and it stemmed from uh
me being unhappy oh dude I was a sloth
uh now that I look back at it I mean I
was falling asleep at work I was oh [__]
this this person sucks man I I just it
wasn't it wasn't healthy
um and and so I I obviously I recognize
that now and uh
it was uh we we both grew um from that
situation it just you know we've learned
and we've uh We've reconnected and it's
been it's been fantastic and you know I
love you to death you've been uh
so it's been it's been it's been good
yeah yeah I mean that that's kind of how
it goes I think we've all got to uh you
know if anybody's still listening up to
this point of you know like
we're we're all growing we're all
expanding you know that's something to
take away from that as we're all um uh
you know again to bring up uh ramdas
spiritual teacher that I listened to he
says we're all just walking each other
home you know and and just we're giving
each other Grace and you know we're
we're all just growing and expanding and
becoming new versions of ourselves and
um you know it's it's all okay and you
don't have to be afraid of it you don't
have to like try to keep it off social
media because you have this image to
protect I think that's what we don't
like we don't like the like hey man we
know you're lying but you think you have
to keep lying but we actually just want
you to tell the truth and talk about it
and it's okay that you're human you
don't have to pretend to be this whole
thing you know it's it's uh stop all the
[__] let's just be real you know
that's that's what we all want
isn't that that the John Bellion song
human is all about that concept and
we have we have close friends currently
that do that they try to sweep
everything under the rug instead of just
having the conversation about it
like everything is
nobody faults them
um for making mistakes making errors and
and you know that's that's how you learn
and grow
um and as cliche as it sounds I mean
burying those issues and acting like oh
I don't have an issue oh you know I
everything's okay
um that doesn't facilitate a mentality
change so
you know that's why I'm I'm so so glad
you advocate advocate for uh
being open and honest about our own
struggles and because we are I mean we
are
we also know I
I'd like to think that I'm perfect
um but uh definitely definitely Parker
yeah yeah no allow yourself to be
totally human I think when you deny
those sorts of things they come up in in
other ways there's uh there's this
um Swiss psychologist uh uh Carl Young
who talks about the collective
unconscious and the Shadow Self of us
and you know the parts and that Parts
within us that we deny they come up in
other ways what's called our shadow like
they come up and um you know we're chill
and then suddenly we react and we yell
at someone and then um you know that
hurts to look at so we we back up even
more or they they come up in our
addictions or they um they only come up
anytime that we're drunk or we're doing
drugs or something
um you know and it's just a real part of
being human is is the um the the art of
of self-acceptance like radical
self-acceptance is what I like to say
it's um it's like it's okay to mess up
like the truth of it is you know maybe
we don't have words for it maybe we
we're not all this like deep and as
mushy as I seem to push everybody into
you you know but like
you know what you could lay out Keenan
you could lay out everything wrong
you've ever done on a plate and I have
to read it out loud to you on a bolded
list and at the end I'll still say cool
man I still love you you know it's like
like we our minds tell us this incorrect
thing that that we uh that we aren't
lovable because of these things that
happen or we aren't
um you know we we won't be accepted if
everybody knew the truth of who we are
in in this mistakes that we've made or
whatever but it's I mean everybody's
walking around with that and I'm just
anybody listening let me give you
permission to just accept that you've
messed up except that you aren't perfect
except that I'm not perfect except that
you could tell anybody these things and
they're still they're still going to
love you I mean you know maybe if you've
like you secretly murder cats every
Tuesday night like maybe that's like
something you should like I don't really
want to be friends with someone like
that but but you know like maybe you
accidentally murdered one cat one time
and you're driving and you know it's
okay I'm just saying like like dude
you're still lovable outside of your
mistakes or your shortcomings or if
you're or if you're miserable inside
because because you're you're overweight
and you don't feel good like dude it's
okay you're still the person who you
really are who I'm really friends with I
love that person and whatever mistakes
you made is okay yeah as long as you've
known me I mean I am
uh very thick skin but also very bull
headed and not an emotional type of
person and
you know for me to recognize and and to
even for me to say that yeah well I was
unhappy at the time like that it's a
pretty big step for somebody like me
um but yeah but and that's what I think
people need to hear to grow and change
because we're all different I mean I'm I
I'm a pretty uh how would you describe
it I mean I'm pretty uh not
anti-emotional but pretty uh not cold
but uh not a not a feelings uh not a
talk about my feelings type of guy
yeah yeah I mean you kind of like you're
Direct in no [__] but also I I mean
I wouldn't I wouldn't you know as
someone who is an emotional fella you
know like you've also
I haven't felt ignored when I've
expressed myself I I haven't felt that
you shut me out or tell me that what I'm
going through isn't um isn't
um real or something like I like I I
don't think that um you know I I don't
think that your reflection of how you
are uh comes across as someone who
doesn't listen to to other people I
think that uh you know uh this is corny
but I think like your compassionate side
shines through whether you want it to or
not man you know and I also think that
you know as much as my journey with
mental health
um has like led me to a place where I
feel that I can connect with people on a
much deeper level now that I'm kind of
on the other side of these sorts of
things I think that also I'm sure that
you know you probably have this level of
connection and acceptance for someone
who's you know maybe really overweight
and they're miserable and maybe they
don't know that they're miserable or in
that sort of thing I mean that that
probably creates a connection with you
and other people that you wouldn't have
got if you didn't go through that
yourself so it's really nice
I got a dealer to take care of it if
you're on average yeah he hit me up I
forgot is is there is there any um is
there any long-term effects like is
there any long-term um things that you
need to be worried about with the
surgery that you went through is there
any like
I mean I know you feel great and
everything but like yes how credible is
the body dude that's so crazy yeah not
not at this point no
um when you're when you're just right
right post-op you do have to worry uh
them not suturing your stomach up but
I'm all healed now
lasting effects I mean the only lasting
effect is really uh you can gain all
your weight back because your body is
fighting me
change in nutritional value
um so you can you can gain your weight
back pretty easily and I have I you know
I I fluctuate
quite a bit on a day-to-day basis but
you know I have had some weight gain and
uh try to try to put myself in check the
mental part is the uh is the lasting
effects
um reverting back to I mean I I do a
tribute um so my my biggest issue with
my weight was uh
um
overeating uh it just you know I always
kind of I'm a foodie by Nature um and
and I eat uh it wasn't so much the types
of food I wasn't uh hey I'm gonna eat 75
McDonald's hamburgers
hamburger um I was like hey you know I'm
gonna cook
uh leaving chicken but oh hey
15 of them in one meal so there's always
portion control with me
um and this is It's been a correction on
my portion control but you know it I do
have to keep uh putting myself in check
it it is almost like an eating addiction
um to why I got to where I was
um and you know just because I love good
food
um so that's been the correction between
what I could eat at the time and what I
can eat now has been the biggest hurdle
right yeah I mean I think awareness is
key too of noting like oh man I'm eating
so much I don't feel good about myself
oh I'm eating so much that I'm like
um you know it's it's just just the act
of getting back on track when you when
you bring awareness to it you know it's
again we all have our we all have our
crap we all have our addictions we all
have our our things that are hard for us
specifically like it's it's really you
know everybody's got something you know
everybody's got their vices whatever it
is and it's just kind of a kind of the
act of not giving into it fully letting
yourself live who you are where you are
but uh bringing yourself back to it you
know okay well you know I did have some
fun it was Super Bowl weekend and we did
that and I was eating crazy amounts of
nachos but like cool it's back on Monday
I know that I don't feel feel great
enough to do um you know to show up and
do my job to the best of my ability to
even just mentally because I continued
this like eating seven plates of nachos
a day even after Super Bowl Sunday so
yeah it's just just raining yourself
back in man it's it's um it's cool well
I'm proud of you for taking that leap I
mean that must have been pretty scary to
be honest
I I had fun I actually made lifelong
friends uh from that uh the uh the uh
the doctor go to you only does four
surgeries a day
um and uh the three gals that I had
surgery with
it's off uh all about the same area
and one of them actually just moved to
Tacoma she got a got a new boyfriend
moved to Tacoma so
um we're you know lifelong friends we
talk back and forth we haven't seen each
other since we had surgery but
um it's kind of a you know a subculture
that camaraderie where you
where you understand
um that subculture that that we've all
gone through something and so now we're
by Nature friends
yeah that's cool yeah I like that yeah I
mean it's it's all it's all about trying
to build a community with people who
have uh you know shared experiences I
think I think that's really what it's
about
yeah
well um cool man we are getting up here
um in in time
um I am uh
I do want to make sure I think we
covered everything that we wanted to
cover is there I mean I don't know if
you want to like you probably want to
drop your cell phone number on this but
is there make sure everybody knows like
where to reach you if they have more
questions for you whether that be as a
council person or maybe about the
surgery
um maybe about
um you know yeah yeah whatever it is
maybe they just really resonate with
some of the things that you said and
maybe they want to just communicate with
you so um could you could you let
everybody know where to reach you at and
where to find yeah so my city email is K
Harvey kelso.gov um I tend to keep that
as uh as my city
um
so from the city city side of things
every piece of information that you send
me is the subject of public record
um so somebody effectively could
public records request the email you
sent me so if it is personal
um a personal question you can call text
if I I'll drop myself I don't care it's
360-747-3842 I literally do not care um
call or text
um
why I do what I do um I do have a
personal email it's Harvey um
h-a-r-v-e-y-k-e-67 gmail.com
um and I don't check that every day so I
apologize if I do miss the response
that's kind of my the spam email that
everybody sends their spam to sign up
for so many things that uh I think my
Facebook notifications every Facebook
notification still goes without even
also
Yeah Yeah well yeah and yeah and connect
connect with Keenan on Facebook and
social media and stuff too yeah
no Tick Tock but
you got to get on Tick Tock you know
does it well I bet you you know in the
coming years I'm sure that um people
being hired around you you know as as
younger Generations get into this and
stuff I'm sure there will be an arc or a
time for tick tock and we'll find ways
to make it generally helpful and that um
you know brings more younger people into
these discussions while also keeping
along our older people because it's
about all of us you know not just
not just one way you know it's it's
always there's valuable times
um for for every perspective I think so
and go buy my feet picks on only fans oh
yeah unsubscribed I am subscribed I laid
in bed for an hour this morning looking
at them
it's crazy that people are actually
making uh exuber amounts of money on
that sort of thing it's very rare a
weird world we live in yeah um okay cool
man well let's uh let's end with like
one more question let's um
well let's go with uh what's something
over the next so think forward in your
life over the next five to ten years
what's something that you want to remind
yourself of what's something that you
want to keep at the Forefront of your
mind like from from an internal
perspective maybe or um you know just
just whatever pops in mind so so looking
forward into your future what's
something that you want to like give
yourself a continuous message about
anything come up
hmm that stuff
um I'd say hanging my hat
uh on things that I have achieved that
I'm proud of
um so I was just awarded the Community
leader of
for the Cal salami Chamber of Commerce
and continuing uh and that's that's
because I put in the work to to earn
that uh But continuing
projects and things that I can hang my
hat on that I'm proud of
um keeping those in the Forefront
because that's really why I do what I do
and although I wasn't the
wasn't the driving force behind the Ada
accessible Park
um in fact it took me a
took me some uh some buy-in uh to to
Really accept that it is necessary
um from the council member that was
proposing it and took the lead on it uh
but projects like that are I think
things that I can hang my hat on and be
proud of and keeping those in the
Forefront of my of my mind because those
are really why I do what I do
um and the impactful change that
projects like that can have on on a
community even if it is as simple as
completing a streetlight project where
all of our street lights are changed to
LED
um to to
Aid in that crime reduction projects
like that that I can really uh hang my
hat on and say hey I'm proud that I
voted the band
um keeping those in the forefrontamental
that's that's going to be important for
micro future
yeah yeah I like that and you know I
think it's helpful for us to like take a
step back and sometimes just you know
thank ourselves in a way and like hey
you know I'm proud to actually
accomplish that thing you know because
you know before long we might get to the
end of our life and realize that we did
actually accomplish a lot of the things
that we wanted to but we never really
slowed down and kind of Pat ourselves on
the back and really cool like you know
in some ways we never really arrive but
uh in a lot of ways
um I think uh you know we accomplish a a
lot of the stuff that we set out to do
you know it doesn't always look exactly
how we wanted it to but um it is it is
helpful to to take a step and go huh
cool I'm proud of myself you know and
then then you know it's right back to
work a lot of times but uh to take a
second at least
it never ends that's for sure yeah cool
man well uh you know I commend you for
opening up uh I appreciate you coming on
to the podcast
um I I always appreciate appreciate our
discussions
um
um you know as I uh I'll have to have
you back on in the in the coming times I
I have intentions like my my posting is
pretty few and far in between these days
um once my work life gets a little more
stable I have some things in the works
but I would like to go back to I I would
like to be posting at least once a week
on the podcast so um we'll definitely
get you on in the next uh you know in
the coming absolutely I'm happy to talk
from any perspective uh I know it
doesn't sound as attractive but the the
risk management and insurance side of
things or my previous life is the parole
probation I got stories for days so
a good conversation as always but I
really appreciate the opportunity yeah
excellent cool
um all right listeners you know where to
find him love yourselves Keenan have so
much fun at Watershed tomorrow man drink
drink start drinking your water and
stuff now like do your do your um uh you
need to do some water enemas some
Gatorade enemas some uh um some coffee
enemas you need to you need to be
putting water in all holes that are
available look what I've used
you can just drink some liquid ideas too
or regular IVs yeah those as well all
right man well much love buddy um I will
talk to you soon everybody listening
please love yourself and get a hold of
Keenan if you want to talk to him and we
will see you next episode Peace Out
hello and welcome to the junkyard love
podcast
[Music]
at what age do we learn how to have
better conversations
at what age should we learn to have
better conversations with ourselves
[Music]
knowledge is power
reality is
[Music]